性别之战
字幕由SSK字幕组倾情译制
字幕仅供学习，勿用于商
转载请注明出处，版权归片方所有
SSK字幕组
新浪微博@SSK字幕组
官网：www.sskzmz.com
SSK字幕组
翻译 少少 Bellatrix XY  庄子 mimic
翻译 来入梦 默默吼
校对 小P
压制 hhjie
特效/总监 王祖贤老婆
性别之战
比利·简·金用一个
A great way to win a championship.
精彩的大力扣杀
With a strenuous brilliant smash...
结束了比赛
...Billie Jean King is the...
成为1972年美国冠军
...1972 champion of the United States!
今日早些时候 比利·简·金续写了
Earlier today, Billie Jean King continued
她创纪录的一年
what has already been a record year...
以六比四 七比六的比分在决胜局中
...with an exciting 6-4, 7-6 win
战胜罗茜·卡萨尔斯 取得了激动人心的胜利
over Rosie Casals in a sudden-death tiebreaker.
这场胜利让她成为
Billie Jean's triumph makes her
史上最成功的女运动员
the most successful woman player of all time...
这引来一位特别的粉丝向她致电
...and prompts a phone call from a very special fan:
那就是尼克松总统
President Nixon.
您好 总统先生
Hello, Mr. President.
我想祝贺你
Well, I just wanted to congratulate you.
很高兴看见加州同胞能得到
And I'm glad to see a fellow Californian
这超过十万美元的奖金
gets over $100,000.
我也很高兴能成为第一个
And I'm glad to be the first woman
获此殊荣的女人
to do it, too.
祝你一切顺利
Well, I wish you well,
这一年你的表现真的很出色
and you've had a really marvelous year.
谢谢 总统先生 非常感谢您的祝福
Thank you, Mr. President. Thank you very much, sir.
只在今天闪光
Being queen for the day
对这位“金”女士来说还不是全部
is not enough for this King.
我的想法会惊世骇俗
I bet you my head's too big.
她公开表达了诉求
She's been outspoken in her demands
要求所有女运动员都能得到涨薪
for higher pay for all women players.
当心了 各位
Watch out, guys.
这位娇小的女士势不可挡啊
There's no stopping this little lady.
比利·简·金庆祝了胜利
Billie Jean King celebrated her win with a big...
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
让我们热烈欢迎
...please welcome 1972
1972年美国网球公开赛女单冠军
U.S. Open Women's Singles Champion...
比利·简·金
...Billie Jean King.
看这个了吗
Have you seen this?
没 你来了 格拉迪斯
No. Hey, Gladys.
想跳舞吗
You want a dance?
我更想要把枪
I want a gun.
他们大半夜的
They just snuck this out
就这么不声不响地放出消息 卑鄙小人
in the middle of the night. Lowlifes.
太过分了
This is outrageous.
上面到处都是杰克·克莱默的指纹
And it's got Jack Kramer's fingerprints all over it.
可不是吗
You're absolutely right it does.
我知道哪能找到他
I know where he's hiding.
要一起吗
You want to come?
不 不必了 你们去忙吧
No. No, you go do your thing.
不过祝你们好运
But good luck.
-谢谢你 亲爱的 -没关系 克莱默先生
-Thank you very much, honey. -Sure, Mr. Kramer.
-谢谢 -不客气
-Thank you. -Of course.
不能就这么放过他们
They won't get away with it.
喔哦
Uh-oh.
您不能进去
You can't go in there.
不好意思
Excuse me.
请等一下
Wait a minute.
找到你老巢了 惊讶吧
Surprised in their lair.
真是意外惊喜啊
This is an unexpected pleasure.
天啊 二位都风姿绰约 如果我可以这么说的话
My goodness, you both look sensational, if I may say.
你不可以
You may not.
这里不是你们能进的地方
You're not supposed to be in here, you know.
因为我是女人还是因为我是犹太人呢 鲍勃
Because I'm a woman or because I'm a Jew, Bob?
没有的事 欢迎你们来这儿 坐吧
Please, you're welcome here. Have a seat.
二位有什么需要吗
What can we do for you?
要不要喝点什么
Would you like a glass of something maybe?
不用了 谢谢 杰克
No, thank you, Jack.
在我忍不住杀了你之前
I find it's best to be clear before
最好先说明白
committing cold-blooded murder, so...
解释清楚
...clarify...
这份新闻稿
...the press release.
当然可以
Ah, yes.
上面说你向男单冠军
It says here that you're offering
支付了一万两千美元奖金
the men's winner $12,000...
而女单冠军只有一千五百美元
...and $1,500 to the women's.
合同条款就是如此规定的
Those are the terms.
男单比赛的奖金要高
The men's prize needs to be that high
才能吸引最好的运动员来打
to attract the best players.
这样是为了把这项赛事
We're trying to make this
办成美国最具名望的赛事
the most prestigious tournament in America.
给女运动员的奖金史上最低
And paying the women less than ever
就能让这项赛事更具名望了吧
makes it more prestigious. Uh...
其实 问题只是我们能提供些什么
Well, it's simply a question of what we can afford.
大家愿意花钱看男人打球
People pay to see the men play.
他们能吸引观众
They're the draw.
他们的吸引力多了八倍吗
They're eight times more of a draw?
你说什么
Sorry?
你们给男单冠军的钱 刚好
You're offering the men's winner
是女单冠军的八倍
eight times that of the women.
我们吸引的观众只有八分之一吗
Do we bring in an eighth of the crowd?
我不知道具体的比例 可是
I don't know percentages, but...
现如今女单决赛卖出的票
They sold the exact same amount of tickets
和男单决赛一样多
to the women's final today as the men's.
-是这样吧 杰克 -现如今 我想是吧
-Isn't that right, Jack? -Today, yeah, I suppose so.
卖票一样多 奖金也应该一样多 我觉得这样才合理
Same sales, same prize money. Makes sense to me.
哎呀 讲点道理吧
Oh, come on. Be reasonable.
我们根本不可能提供这么多女单奖金
There's no way that we could afford that.
理由是什么 杰克
What's your argument, Jack?
首先
For one thing,
男人得养家
the men have families that they have to support.
在我家 我才是经济支柱
I'm the main breadwinner in my family.
好吧 好吧
Yeah. Yeah.
是这样
Look.
简单的说 男人打比赛 看着更过瘾
The men are simply... more exciting to watch.
不可否认
They are.
-他们速度更快 -确实
-They're faster. -Fact.
-身体素质更好 -没错
-And stronger. -Fact.
竞争欲更强
And more competitive.
就是这样
Just a fact.
也不是你们的错 就是 男女天生的差距
It's not your fault, it's just... biology.
我要说的不是这个 我是说男女比赛卖出同样数量的票
That's not my point. We sell the same amount of tickets.
抱歉 你要的是不可能实现的
I'm sorry. It's not going to happen.
好吧 你们真要这样的话
Well, if that's the way it is...
我们以后就拒绝参加这项赛事
...we'll boycott the tournament.
真的
Fact.
既然如此
Well, now...
我们会怀念你们漂亮的脸蛋 不过还是好走不送
...we'll sure miss your pretty faces, but go right ahead.
我们不仅会抵制
Not only will we boycott,
还会建立我们自己的赛事
we'll set up our own tournament.
真的
Fact.
和西南太平洋同一时间进行
At the exact same time as the Pacific Southwest.
也是真的
Fact.
言出必行 记得给我寄门票 晚安了 女士们
Be sure and send me tickets. You have a good night, ladies.
做梦去吧她们
That'll never happen.
我们真要这么做吗
Are we really gonna do this?
当然要这么做
Sure we're gonna do this.
要怎么做呢
How are we gonna do this?
不知道
No idea.
也是
Right.
今天忙吗
Did you have a busy day?
一刻没歇着 大脑都停转了
Run off my feet. Not a minute to think.
无论你觉得我在那边应该做什么
Whatever it is I'm supposed to be
我都不会做的 普丽西拉
doing down there, Priscilla, I'm not doing it.
爸爸跟我说他觉得
Well, Daddy told me that he thinks
你是公司不可或缺的人
you're an integral part of the company.
不可或缺吗
Huh. Integral.
我桌子上的订书机也不可或缺
Like the stapler on my desk.
它很稳定啊
Well, it's steady,
你现在需要的就是稳定
and it's what you need right now.
我知道
I know. I know.
我想知道里边有多少个胡椒粒
I wonder how much peppercorns are in here.
我也不知道 朱尼尔
I don't know, Junior.
要我说得有一千个吧
I'd say about a thousand.
不会吧 我觉得里边至少有五千
No way! There got to be at least five thousand in there.
我赌一块钱 里边有一千个
I'd put a dollar on a thousand.
-小子 -喔不 不可以
-Young man. -Whoa, no, no, no.
小子 不要在饭桌上赌博
Young man, we do not gamble at the dinner table.
在哪都不能赌博 鲍比
We do not gamble anyplace, Bobby.
没错 在哪都不能赌博
Exactly. We do not gamble anyplace.
不能赌博
No, we do not.
就一块钱
One dollar.
来吧
Come on.
好了好了
All right.
哦 你猜怎么着
Oh, you know what?
我想起来 我得回趟办公室
I just remembered, I need to go back to the office
还有工作没做完
and finish up some work.
现在去吗
Now?
你父亲一直都很看好我 亲爱的
Your father has been so supportive, honey,
我不想让他失望
that I don't want to let him down.
晚饭很好吃 谢谢你
Delicious. Thank you.
回见了 孩子
See you later, kiddo.
我押杰克双倍
I'm doubling down on Jack.
鲍比 这边有人出一千二
Bobby, we got $1,200 on the table!
一千二啊 兄弟
$1,200, buddy!
鲍比 养这么漂亮的狗
Bobby, you're not allowed
太犯规了
to have dogs that good-looking.
丢一球
Miss one!
他顾不过来了 上吧
We got him on the run, here we go!
他顾不过来了
We got him on the run!
把椅子放过去
Put the chair out there!
放两把 每把给你加五百块
Two chairs and I'll raise you $500 each.
让狗来打吧
Give the racket to the dog!
那可不行
Oh, too good for you.
杰克 你太弱了
Jack, for the love of God!
-可恶 -打得不错 杰克
-Damn it. -Good game, Jack.
我以为这次能赢你 真的
I thought I had you this time, I really did.
你很努力了
That was a fine, fine effort.
打得不错 很努力了
Great try, great try.
不 别过来
No, don't come over here.
想什么呢 杰克 鲍比可是世界冠军
What do you expect, Jack? Bobby's the world champ.
不 我有优势 那可是三对一啊
No, I had an advantage. It was three against one.
三对一
It was three against one.
知道吗 他一直押我
You know what? He keeps betting me,
我都不知道怎么办了
I don't know what to do about it.
杰克的优势就是 他输得起
The thing about Jack is, he can afford to lose.
不能不管普丽西拉啊 鲍比
You got to think about Priscilla, Bobby.
她会怎么说你
What is she gonna say?
-你还没离婚啊 鲍比 -跟离了差不多
-You still married, Bobby? -Oh, barely.
让他老婆看见他开劳斯莱斯就得离婚了
He sure will be if he shows up in a Rolls-Royce.
让他老婆看见他坐劳斯莱斯就离不成了
He sure as hell won't be if he shows up in a Rolls-Royce.
为什么
Why?
鲍比自己都会觉得不好说
Even Bobby will find it tough
说了没人信
to talk his way out of that one.
宝贝 今天真是不可思议
"Oh, honey, this crazy day!
这不起眼的家伙白送了我一辆银影
"This guy on the corner just gave me a Silver Shadow."
这么说有用吗
Think that'll cut it?
谁会信呢
Talk his way out of it?
他赢来了一辆劳斯莱斯
The man just won himself a Rolls-Royce!
赫博 你不明白
Herb, you're not getting it.
鲍比戒赌了
Bobby doesn't gamble anymore.
他戒赌了啊
Oh, he don't gamble anymore!
不不
No, no, no.
我一周去一次匿名戒赌小组
Gamblers Anonymous once a week,
一周去看两次心理医生 我已经改过自新了
shrink twice a week. I'm a reformed man.
-给你 -哦好极了
-There you are. -Oh, there you go.
知道吗 其实 罗尼有一点说对了
You know what? Actually, Lornie's got a point.
劳斯莱斯太大了 不好藏啊
That vehicle's kind of big to hide.
杰克 你可以帮忙保管一阵子
Jack, why don't you just keep it for a little while?
你是说我不适合跟人打赌吗
You saying I'm not good for a bet?
不 不是这个意思 别让车闲着
No, no, no. Just keep the engine warm
别刮了就行
and don't nick up the paint.
“十万美金姑娘”
"$100,000 Girl?"
长青巡回赛都挣不了这么多钱
You don't see even a senior tour making a hundred G's.
她给自己估价比这还高呢
Oh, she reckons she ought to get more than that.
要和男人一样多
Same as the men.
拿了十万还不满意
She's not happy with $100,000?
那个叫比利·简·金的有什么毛病
That Billie Jean King, what is her problem?
鲍比 记住 现在都是
Bobby, you got to remember, nowadays it's all
这个平等 那个平等的
equality this, equality that.
她们都开始烧内衣了 老天爷
They're burning bras, for God's sake.
凭什么给女人
Why would they ever pay the women
和男人一样多的钱呢
the same as the guys?
我能说的就是 看着姑娘穿着短裙
All I can tell you is that there is nothing wrong
到处追球 还是挺不错的
with a nice girl in a short skirt chasing a ball.
美国公开赛我都赢了
You know, I won the goddamn U.S. Open.
管他是比利·简·金 还是别的女人 我都能赢
I could beat Billie Jean King or any of those women.
赢了她们有巡回赛那么多奖金吗
But are they offering me equal prize money on the tour?
不好意思没有 只能给我花生吃
No, sir, I'm getting peanuts.
你可以开个赌啊
Hey, there's a bet for you.
赌什么
What's that?
鲍比·里格斯对战比利·简·金
Bobby Riggs vs. Billie Jean King.
我会花大价钱看这比赛
I'd pay a lot to see that.
大家听一下
Hey, everybody?
我知道大家都在冒险
I know what you're all risking,
因为我也在拿同样的东西冒险
because I'm risking the exact same thing.
更多
More.
不 没有更多 是同样的
No, not more. The same.
我们都在拿自己的职业生涯冒险
We're all putting our careers on the line for this.
感谢你们的勇敢
So I just want to thank you for your bravery.
还有你们的胆量
And your balls.
我们每次活动前都要做发型吗
Are we gonna get our hair done before every event?
我还挺喜欢的
Because I could get used to this.
仅此一次 因为有媒体
The salon is a once-only because the press is here.
而且我很喜欢你们
And because I love you so much.
明天媒体不在了 我也不喜欢你们了
Tomorrow the press won't be here and I won't love you.
这次巡回赛资金有限 女士们
This is a budget tour, ladies...
所以要委屈大家共用房间了
which means you will be sharing rooms.
现在可以开始
So you might as well start
互相认识一下了
getting to know each other now.
我可以和瓦尔一起睡
I call bunking with Val!
我以为你能拉来赞助呢 格拉迪斯
I thought you were gonna get us a sponsor, Gladys.
我找过
I... was. I...
在找 罗茜
...am, Rosie.
只不过现在我们没钱了 所以别说了
It's just that right now we are broke, so shut up.
那我们的奖金怎么办
Well, wait. What about our prize money?
瓦尔 现在担心奖金有什么用
Oh, Val, why are you worried about prize money?
赢了才有奖金拿呢
You only get that if you win.
好了 还有三十分钟
All right, you've got 30 minutes before
就要见媒体了
you show your faces to the press.
-你好 -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
我老乱动 是吧
I've been moving around too much, haven't I?
是啊
Yeah.
不好意思 我就是 太激动了
I'm sorry, I've been, uh... I'm excited.
也可能是紧张之类的
Or nervous or something.
你们都是网球选手吗
You're all tennis players?
是啊 你平时不看网球吗
Yeah. You don't watch tennis?
看不了 我没有电视
Oh, no. I don't have a TV.
但是你们的所作所为我很钦佩
But I admire what you guys are doing.
好像你们这次让男人开始注意
Sounds like you girls are getting men to pay attention
女人的呼声了
to what you're saying for once.
知道什么才能真正引起他们注意吗
You know what would really get their attention?
性罢工
A sex strike.
什么 那会杀敌一千自损八百的
What? That would punish us just as much as the men.
我一点都不怀念
I don't think I'd even miss it.
我前任在床上时就像在修奥兹莫比尔汽车
My ex went about it like he was fixing the carburetor
的汽化器
on the Oldsmobile.
就是死活打不着火
And he could never get that damn car to start.
罗茜 你够了
Rosie, come on!
至少女人还知道汽化器在哪
At least women know where the carburetor is.
那么
So...
比利·简
...Billie Jean...
你想怎么做
...what do you want?
什么怎么做
What do you mean?
你的头发 要怎样的造型呢
With your hair. What do you want to do with it?
哦
Oh.
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
只要不让它贴在脸上就行了
You can just get it out of my face.
你不在意外表吗
You don't care about how you look?
你这么漂亮
Someone as pretty as you?
呃 我 我不
Uh, it's... I'm not...
不漂亮 我...
...pret... I mean, I don't...
谢谢你这么说
Thank you for... for saying that.
你叫什么来着
What's your name again?
玛丽莲
Marilyn.
能让我稍微给你剪一下吗
Would you let me just... give you a little trim?
会让你感觉焕然一新的
It'll make you feel like a whole new person.
我不觉得发型能有那么神奇的作用
I don't think a haircut's ever made me feel quite like that.
是香水味吗
Is that perfume?
薰衣草精油
It's lavender oil.
在手腕上涂一点能让顾客放松
I put it on my wrists just to relax the customers.
很好闻
It's nice.
我很喜欢
I love it.
比利·简
Billie Jean!
-快来 -来了
-Come on! -I'm coming!
这就去
All right!
她在里边干什么呢
What is she doing in there?
见到你很高兴
It was nice to meet you.
我也很高兴
Nice to meet you.
忽然想起来
You know what?
我们下个月在圣地亚哥有场比赛
We've got a tournament in San Diego, actually,
我这有好多票
next month, and I have a lot of tickets.
你带上大家去看吧
So you could just bring everyone and...
-比利·简 走了 -很有意思的
-Billie Jean, let's go! -It's a lot of fun.
欢迎大家去看
Yeah, everyone's invited to come.
记得是下个月在圣地亚哥
Next month in San Diego.
谢谢你
So... thank you again.
谢谢
Thank you.
可算来了
Finally.
我们要晚了
We're gonna be late!
你觉得那儿会有好看的摄影师吗
Do you think there'll be any cute photographers?
比奇斯 我知道他很好看 但是我们得走了
Peaches, I know he's very cute, but let's go.
女生们 都排好队
Girls, get in line.
准备好 我们要签合同了
Get ready, and let's get these contracts signed.
欢迎来到国际女子职业网联
Welcome to the WTA.
感谢你加入我们
Thank you so much for joining us.
签了之后就是职业选手了
That makes you a professional.
罗茜 我很荣幸
Rosie, it's a pleasure.
走起来 不要磨蹭
Keep this going. Don't dawdle.
你的一美元 比利·简
One dollar, Billie Jean.
对 一美元就够了
Yeah, a whole dollar is right.
我要把它存起来
I'm gonna save it!
谢谢 欢迎来到国际女子职业网联
Thank you. Welcome to the WTA.
我们该坐在哪儿
Where do we sit?
比利·简
Billie Jean.
猜猜谁来了
Guess who showed up.
朱迪 拜托 别害羞了
Judy, come on. Don't be shy.
今天是激动人心的一天 女孩们 情绪高涨点
This is an exciting day, girls. Look excited.
很感谢你
Thank you very much.
好的 女孩们 过来 开始入座
Okay, girls. Come on, let's start sitting, please.
今天很重要 女士们 克里 坐在下一个位置
It's a big day, ladies. Kerry, you're next.
我们要照一张重要的照片
We're gonna take a big picture.
比利·简…
Billie Jean...
你正在做的事 是个严重的错误
...what you're doing here is a big mistake.
杰克 那你还能给我们什么别的选择吗
Are you here to give us another option, Jack?
我以美国草地网球协会的名义过来
On behalf of the USLTA,
是为了让你们这群女孩不要太冲动
I'm here to ask you girls not to do anything hasty.
那你能给我们什么
So what are you offering?
我能让你们保住
I'm offering to keep you in
在美国草地网球协会中的一席之地
the United States Lawn Tennis Association.
你是想除我们的名
You're kicking us out.
我现在做的事 让你成为我们的敌人
You do this, you're becoming our rivals.
我们别无选择
We have no option.
我会想念你漂亮的脸蛋的 杰克
I'll sure miss your pretty face, Jack,
但你走好不送
but you go right ahead.
好极了 那我们让比利
Great. And then we'll put Billie...
马上就是伟大的时刻了
I'm gonna have a very exciting moment in a second.
这太伟大了 比利·简呢
This is monumental. Billie Jean?
再等一下
One minute!
如果你不在美国草地网球协会里
If you're not in the USLTA,
你就打不了大满贯了
you can't play the Grand Slams.
打不了温网 什么都打不了
No Wimbledon. No nothing.
我知道
I get it.
但没了世界上最厉害的女球员
But what are your Grand Slams
怎么还称得上大满贯呢
without the greatest women players in the world?
大满贯也没有那么伟大
They're not so grand.
所以我很感激你能来 杰克 我很感激
So I appreciate you coming, Jack, very much...
但如果你不是来开条件的话
...but if you have nothing to offer us,
我还有个合同要签
I have a contract to sign.
再见了 杰克
Bye, Jack.
好的 女孩们 拿好你们的一美元 真好看
Okay, girls, hold those dollars up. Beautiful.
笑一笑 这又不是葬礼
Smile, girls. This isn't a funeral.
拿好那张美元
Hold up that dollar.
保持微笑 女士们
Keep smiling, ladies,
但我们刚刚被美国草地网球协会除名了
but we've just been kicked out of the USLTA.
什么
What?
摇一摇给杰克看看
Wave them so Jack can see them!
对 这是一美元 记住它只是一美元
Yep, it's a dollar, girls. Remember that... One dollar.
就这些吗 你们所有人就吃这些吗
Is that it? For all of you?
能给我拿下番茄酱吗
Can I have some ketchup?
谁死了吗
Who died?
嘿 格拉迪斯
Hey, Gladys.
噢 我明白了 都是我的错
Oh, I get it. It's all my fault.
好吧 格拉迪斯为你们这些忘恩负义的人
Well, Gladys has got just the thing
准备了一样东西
for you miserable ingrates.
香烟吗
Cigarettes?
女士们和女士们 请允许我为你们介绍
Ladies and gentle-ladies, may I present to you
弗吉尼亚锦标赛
the Virginia Slims Championships.
格拉迪斯·海德曼和菲利普·莫里斯联合出品
A Gladys Heldman/Philip Morris co-production.
让你在美国每寸土地上
Smoking your guts out across
吸个痛快
the United States of America...
与之作为交换的是十二月的募集
...in exchange for twelve months funding...
以及 奖金是 请为我敲起鼓点
...and prize money of... drum roll, please...
七千美金
...$7,000.
-真的吗 -好极了 老姐
-Really? -Way to go, Mom!
-每场锦标赛吗 -每场锦标赛
-For every tournament? -For every tournament.
这会让你们懒散的每次发球重拾激情
That ought to perk up your lousy second serve.
你们负责打球 我负责抽烟
You do the tennis, I'll do the smoking.
我的孩子们 从现在开始 我们有钱了
My girls, from now on we are fully funded.
我给泰德·泰宁打了个电话
I put in a call to Ted Tinling,
她会当我们巡回路上的私人服装设计师
who's gonna be our personal couturier on tour.
你们每个人都会有
You're each gonna have your own tennis dresses
专门为你们设计的网球裙
designed specially for you.
我还给每个拿起球拍
And I put in a call to every woman
打过网球的女人打了电话
who's ever picked up a racket.
猜猜有谁已经加入了
Guess who's already signed on.
我来 我来
Oh. Oh.
不要猜了 是玛格丽特·考特
Don't guess. Margaret Court.
“铁臂女将” 比利·简 你害怕了吗
"The Arm." Billie Jean, are you scared?
我能拿下她的
I can take her.
-真的吗 -当然
-Yeah? -Yeah.
别担心 你不久就有机会的
Well, you'll get your chance soon enough.
服务员 每个人一份冰激凌圣代
Waitress! Ice cream sundaes all around.
我们有钱了
We're in the money.
但是
But...
不是所有人啊 就给我的桌子和这两人
...not all around. Just my table and these two.
我们试试金凤花 柠檬那种颜色
Let's try the buttercup, lemony sort of hue.
但我不觉得它和你的设计搭
But I don't really feel it pops with your complexion,
那我们试试蓝色
so let's try the blue.
噢 棒极了 泰德
Oh! It's wonderful, Ted.
-你喜欢吗 -我爱死它了
-You like it? -I love it!
我们尊贵的草地网球协会
And what will the esteemed
会对此发表什么意见呢
Lawn Tennis Association say about this?
女士们先生们 我向你们介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, I give you,
在网球历史上首次出现的东西
for the first time in the history of tennis...
色彩
...color!
这会把那些老顽固吓死的
The shock will kill the old dears.
这里是频率87
87 kmrp.
现在是七点二十分
It's twelve minutes after 7:00,
我们作为网球粉丝 今天在演播室里
and we are privileged, tennis fans...
很荣幸地请到了
...to have the great Billie Jean King
著名的比利·简·金 和这群
in the studio with us today, along with a...
活泼可爱的国际女子职业网联的运动员们
...A lot of very lively WTA tennis players.
对观众打声招呼吧 女士们
Say hi, ladies.
大家好
Hi.
有传言说你们成为了
The word is that you gals are renegades
网球联盟中的变节者 是真的吗
from the tennis establishment. Is that right?
是的
Yeah.
美国草地网球协会
The U.S. Lawn Tennis Association
不愿意给我们女人公平的待遇
wasn't really giving us women our fair share,
所以我们就想
so we thought...
“嘿 那我们自己来吧”
..."Hey, we'll do it on our own."
明知山有虎 偏向虎山行
Taking the bull by the horns.
没错
That's right.
实际情况是这样
Here's the inside scoop:
“我们包办了一切”
We do everything.
我们搞定场地
We are the ones laying down the courts.
我们来卖票
We're selling tickets.
我们做宣传
We're doing publicity.
我们还要在期间找时间训练
And we have to fit in practice somewhere in between there.
我们也在努力让网球
We are also trying to get tennis away
从老旧的乡村俱乐部运动的定位中走出来
from the stuffy old country club sport.
我们想要它普及到每个人
We want it to be for everybody.
现在是1973年了 所以我们可以改变一些东西了
It's 1973, so... we could update a couple things.
现在 你们在锦标赛中
Now, you all play each other
对手就是彼此
in the tournaments and...
而且你们也住在一起
...you room together as well.
所以如果你非要和一个刚打败你的人
So how does that work when you have to room
或是刚被你打败的人住在一起
with somebody who just beat you...
那该怎么办呢
...or who you just defeated?
这没事 因为赢的经常是我
It's fine, because I usually win.
噢 那也不一定哦
Oh. That's not true at all.
如果不和罗茜住在一起就可以
It's fine if you're not rooming with Rosie.
噢 我知道了 别和罗茜住在一起 大家要听好噢
Oh, okay. Don't room with Rosie... That's the message.
我们只是 因为更高的理想而集合在一起
We're also, you know, united for a greater cause.
所以我们更关注别的事
So it keeps the focus on something else.
它是比比赛更重要的东西
It's bigger than the match.
很高兴见到你 再见
Nice to meet you. Bye!
你们都觉得自己是女性的解放者吗
Do you all consider yourselves women's libbers?
-噢 当然 -我是这么觉得的
-Oh, sure. -I think so.
我们现在做这些事 是想证明
What we're doing here is trying to prove
女人应当被给予平等的待遇和尊重
that women should be paid and respected equally.
我们和男人一样惹人喜欢
We're just as entertaining as the men.
你们肯定比男人们更可爱
You're definitely cuter than the men.
路上你们一定都有些孤独
It must get a little lonely out there on the road.
你们想念你们的丈夫吗
Don't you ever miss your husbands?
当然 我们很想
Sure. Of course we do.
我每天都和赖瑞打电话
I talk to Larry on the phone every day.
我们都很习惯 事实上 我们本来就聚少离多
We're used to it. As pros, we're not home very often.
我们中有些还没有丈夫呢
And some of us don't have husbands.
哇哦
Whoa.
单身的男性们 你们可要听好了
Single men, you heard it here first.
这里有些单身女性噢
Some of these ladies are single themselves.
尤其是比奇斯 快来吧
Especially Peaches. Come on out.
-对带上你的女儿们 -或是你的儿子们
-Yeah, bring your daughters. -Or your sons.
或是带上每个人
Or bring everyone.
你可以带上一家人
You could bring your whole family.
这就是我们这次巡游的意义所在
That's the point of this tour.
这是为所有人准备的 完全是为了高兴
It's for everyone, and it's a whole lot of fun.
你们听到了 伙计们 下面我们要接入音乐了
You heard it here, folks. We'll get in more music,
但我们有些票可以赠送
but we got tickets to give away,
所以给我们打电话吧
so give us a call.
感谢你们的到来 女士们
Thanks for coming by, ladies.
感谢你让我们来
Thank you for having us.
-祝你们好远 -大家都来吧
-Good luck. -Come on out!
这里一点都不豪华啊
It's not exactly the Ritz.
玛格丽特·考特 欢迎来到修道院
Margaret Court! Welcome to the nuthouse.
-嗨 泰德 -嗨 玛格丽特
-Hi, Ted. -Hey, Margaret.
比利·简
Billie Jean.
如果你在找饭店或是按摩馆
If you're looking for the restaurant or the spa
或者游泳池 这里全都没有
or the swimming pool, there isn't one.
但是如果你想找票的话
But if you're looking for the tickets
你可以在十字路口卖
you're gonna sell at the intersection...
就是这些
they're right here.
希望你有个美好的夜晚 亲爱的宝宝
Have a lovely evening. Darling child.
她一直都不喜欢我
She's never liked me.
谁 格拉迪斯吗
Who? Gladys?
不 那个厉害的比利·简·金
No, the great Billie Jean King.
亲爱的 你只管在球场上
You just do your talking
用实力说好了
on the court, honey.
过来 跳过来
Come on, cross over!
你可以的 真棒
You can do it. There you go.
小心短吻鳄
Watch out for the alligators.
我在注意短吻鳄
I'm watching out for the alligator.
你要小心短吻鳄
You watch out for the alligator.
我正在过摇晃的桥
I'm going across the wobbly bridge.
你妈妈一直在看我们 过来
Your mother's always watching us. Right here.
过来 好的
Right here. Okay.
那会把你烧成灰烬
That'll burn you right to the bones.
那是流沙
That's quicksand.
那是流沙 对 强酸性流沙
That's quicksand, all right. Acid quicksand.
所以你从没有见过你的兄弟姐妹
That's why you never see any of your siblings.
这儿有两块石头 别跌倒流沙里
Two rocks. Don't fall in the quicksand!
别跌倒流沙里
Don't fall in the quicksand!
好的 还有一块石头 我们就可以到了
Okay. One more rock and we're there.
-好 你快到了 -要是我做不到呢
-Good. You got it. -What if I don't make it?
你可以做到的 你是里格斯家的人
You can make it! You're a Riggs,
你会做到的 一 二 三
you're gonna make it. One, two, three...
哇哦
Whoa, whoa.
好吧 我们几乎成功了
Well, we almost made it.
嘿 亲爱的 你能帮我开一下门吗
Hey, honey! Could you get that?
好的
Okay.
我在给朱尼尔读故事
I'm reading Junior a story.
鲍比
Bobby?
你知不知道 额
Do you know anything about a, uh...
劳斯莱斯 太酷了
Rolls-Royce! Cool!
可恶 杰克
Damn it, Jack.
妈妈 里面有台电视
Mom, it's got a TV!
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know. Um...
这是杰克的主意
It was Jack's idea.
你就像个小孩子 你知道吗
You are like a little kid, you know that?
你很擅长哄小孩子
Well, you're good with kids.
我们谈了那么多次
After everything we talked about?
你跟我做过什么保证
Everything you promised me?
好吧 我知道了 给我
Okay, okay, I get it. Give me those.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
-我也能去吗 -不行
-Can I come, too? -No, you can't come.
朱尼尔
Junior!
-好了 -谢谢 考特夫人
-All right. -Thanks, Mrs. Court.
谢谢观看
Thanks for coming.
你喜欢吗
Did you like it?
太棒了
It was amazing.
-感谢你的观看 -谢谢
-Thanks for coming. -Thank you.
-很高兴见到你 -很高兴见到你
-Nice to meet you. -Nice to meet you.
发型不错
Nice hair.
你来了
You came!
你为什么不告诉我 你有这么厉害
Why didn't you tell me how good you are?
啊 算了
Ah, well.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
可以啊 但我不一定会回答
You may. I may not answer it.
你喜欢跳舞吗
Do you like dancing?
喜欢
I do.
真的
Yeah.
我真不敢相信你在场上的样子
I can't believe how you move on the court.
我就像是在看一个
It's like watching some kind of...
野兽
...wild animal.
啊 少来吧 我很高兴你喜欢
Aw, come on. I'm glad you enjoyed it.
喜欢吗 我从没看过这样的画面 就像是
Enjoyed it? I've never seen anything like it! It was...
这肯定很让人兴奋
It must be intoxicating.
什么 打网球吗
What? Playing tennis?
与你相融
Being inside your skin.
抱歉 打扰一下
Excuse me.
我很抱歉打扰你们了
I'm so sorry for doing this.
金女士 我是你的狂热粉丝
Mrs. King, I'm such a huge fan.
噢 很谢谢你
Oh. Thank you so much.
我是迈尔斯
I'm Miles.
迈尔斯 很高兴见到你
Miles. Great to meet you.
你想跳上一曲吗
Do you dance as well as you serve?
哦 谢了 我不
Oh, thanks, I don't think...
今天晚上我们只打算呆在这里 到处看一看
Tonight we're just gonna stay here and watch.
-好吧 -但是很高兴见到你 迈尔斯
-Okay. -But nice to meet you, Miles.
我也是
You, too.
我想跳
I'd love to dance!
啊 好啊
Well, sure thing.
我来帮你涂吗
Let me do yours?
你太完美了
You're perfect.
我马上得走了
I got to go soon.
什么
What?
-不 -对
-No. -Yeah.
我得坐车回洛杉矶了
I got to get a bus back to L.A.
不 那也太晚了
No, it's too late for that.
现在可没有车坐了
You can't take a bus right now.
你可以呆在我的房间里
You can stay in my room.
我房间里有两张床 说实话 没什么不方便的
I've got two beds. Honestly, it's no trouble.
好吧
Okay.
谢啦
Thanks.
没事
Sure. Yeah.
这是我的房间
This is me.
我们的房间
Us.
我的房间
Me.
所以 格拉迪斯以前让我们两人一间
So, Gladys used to make us share rooms,
但我们现在住得起一人一间了
but we can afford our own now.
我总会睡窗边的床
I usually take the bed closest to the window.
不过没关系 你想睡哪张床都可以
But it's fine! Take whichever one you want.
我结婚了
I'm married.
没关系
That's okay.
我也有男朋友了 某种意义上
I've got a boyfriend. Sort of.
但是你
But you, uh...
你
...you...
也会跟女人在一起吗
...with women... too?
没错
Yeah.
-你呢 -没有
-Do you? -No.
从来没有 我
No, never. I'm...
我只跟赖瑞一起过
There's only ever been Larry.
所以
So...
我能吻你吗
...can I kiss you?
嗯
Mmm.
我们可以慢慢来 没关系 没有
We can take it slow, that's okay. There's no...
我必须这样 梅尔
I have to, Mare.
这是我生活里为数不多的可以指望的事
It's one of the few sure things I can count on in life.
得了吧 朗达
Come on, Rhoda.
你爱你妈 你自己也知道
You love your mother and you know it.
我当然爱她
Of course I love her.
我只是觉得她因为
I just think she's holding a grudge because
我没有进她为我选的行业
I didn't go into the profession
而对我耿耿于怀
she picked out for me:
家庭主妇
Housewife.
是我妈妈 她来了
My mother, she's here!
你很美
You're beautiful.
运动新闻中
And in sporting news,
我们转向了女子网球的世界
we turn to the world of women's tennis...
今日比利·简·金与克里斯蒂·佩珍对打
...as Billie Jean King beat Kristy Pigeon today,
两盘比零 就在圣地亚哥进行
two sets to zero, in San Diego.
接下来这次弗吉尼亚女子球队巡回赛将向洛杉矶前进
Next, the Virginia Slims tour heads to Los Angeles.
在棒球领域 洋基队在对红袜队的一败涂地后
In baseball, the Yankees have started 0 and 3
开场打了个零比三
after being swept on the road by the Red Sox.
哦 是赖瑞
Oh, it's Larry.
天呐 要是格拉迪斯怎么办
Oh, God, what if it's Gladys?
天 要是我父母呢
Jesus, what if it's my parents?
他们没有人可以透过电话看过来 对吧
Well, none of 'em can see down the phone, can they?
别开玩笑 别开玩笑 别
Don't joke. Don't joke. Just don't...
什么都别说 好吗
Don't say anything, okay?
安静 安静一点 好吗
Just be quiet. Just be quiet, okay?
喂
Hello?
找到了
Eureka!
喂
Hello?
我找到了 比利·简
Eureka, Billie Jean!
你是谁
Who is this?
我是鲍比 鲍比·里格斯
It's Bobby. Bobby Riggs.
鲍比 你怎么知道我的号码的
Bobby? How'd you get my number?
我给圣地亚哥的每个旅馆打了电话
Called every hotel in San Diego.
听着 我有个超棒的主意
Listen, I had a great idea.
好吧 现在已经过了午夜了 鲍比
Okay. Well, it's after midnight, Bobby,
我们能另找时间再谈吗
so can we talk another time?
你和我 比利·简
You and me, Billie Jean.
三盘 五盘 你来选
Three sets, five sets... Your choice.
你喝多了吗 鲍比
Are you drunk, Bobby?
不 当然没有
No, of course not!
这个怎么样 “男女大对决”
How about this: "Man vs. Woman."
男沙文猪对决毛腿女权主义者
"Male Chauvinist Pig vs. Hairy-Legged Feminist".
没别的意思 你还是个女权主义者 对吗
No offense. You're still a feminist, right?
不 我只是个网球运动员 而恰好是女性
No, I'm a tennis player who happens to be a woman.
没错 那就是你
That's right. That's exactly who you are.
而我是个网球运动员 恰好是男性
And I am a tennis player who happens to be a man...
还放出话来说他可以打败地球上的任何一个女人
...who says that he can beat any woman on the planet.
想想我们能得到多少关注 想想那些钞票
Think of the publicity that we get. Think of the money.
不
No.
三万五大洋
Thirty-five grand.
你从哪里拿到那么多钱的
Where'd you get that kind of money?
-你看 你被吸引了 -我真的没有
-You see? You're tempted. -I'm really not.
我不感兴趣 鲍比 晚安
I'm not interested, Bobby. Good night.
别挂
Don't hang up.
顺便说一句 我有刮腿的
And by the way, I shave my legs.
是谁啊
Who was that?
只是某个老疯骗子想要来场比赛
That was just some crazy old hustler trying to get a game.
希望你别介意
I hope you don't mind.
我借了件衣服当睡衣
I borrowed something to sleep in.
玛丽莲
Marilyn.
啊
Ah.
你要对我做分手演说了 是吗
You're gonna give me the speech, aren't you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
不管我
Whatever I...
感觉如何 我都不能有所表现
...may feel, I can't act on it.
太冒险了 我还有网球巡回赛和
There's too much at stake. I mean the tennis tour and...
嗯
Yeah.
我还有丈夫
And I have my husband.
他是个很棒的
He's a great...
人 要是被他发现了他会心碎的
...person, and he would be heartbroken if he found out.
我父母再也不会对我说话了
And my parents would never speak to me again.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
我懂的
I get it.
那就好
Okay.
哦 给
Oh, hey.
谢谢
Thanks.
-晚安 -晚安
-'Night. -Good night.
嗨
Hi.
喂
Hello?
拉里 你醒着吗
Larry, are you awake?
-爸 -我能上来吗
-Dad? -Can I come up?
好
Okay.
你好啊 孩子
Hey there, kiddo.
嘿
Hey.
就住今晚
Just for tonight.
可能还有明晚
Maybe tomorrow.
没问题 没问题
Sure, sure.
只是一点小小的误会
Oh, a little misunderstanding.
有时候普丽西拉有点炸毛
Sometimes Priscilla goes off the deep end.
哦对了 你看见我的劳斯莱斯了吗
Oh, hey... did you see my Rolls-Royce?
看见了 很酷 老爸
Yeah, that's cool, Dad.
你要住在车里吗
You gonna live in it?
是啊 我可以 我可以 那车够大
Yeah, well, I could. I could. It's big enough.
但是不 不会 我有计划 拉里 伟大的计划
But no, no, no. I got plans, Larry. Big plans.
是哦
Right.
我听说过你的计划
Yeah, well, I've... heard 'em.
全部计划
All of 'em.
晚安 孩子
Good night, kiddo.
晚安 老爸
Good night, Dad.
普丽西拉
Priscilla!
宝贝
Honey!
宝贝 求你了
Honey, come on.
至少给一条干净的内裤嘛
Not even a fresh pair of underpants?
牙刷呢
Toothbrush?
我们能不能谈一谈
Can't we just talk about this?
你知道吗 哦
You know... Oh.
哦
Oh.
谢谢你
Thank you!
我叫鲍比 我是个上瘾者
My name is Bobby and I am an addict.
你好 鲍比
Hi, Bobby.
至少普丽西拉是这么说的
At least that's what Priscilla says.
她要离开我了 除非我戒掉赌博
She's gonna leave me unless I quit gambling.
不过 “赌博”这个词让我很迷惑
Puzzles me, though, that word: "Gambling."
无论何时普丽西拉从车库里开出一辆车
Whenever Priscilla gets a car out of the garage,
她都是在下一个很大的赌注
she's gambling big time.
从来不检查后视镜 把镜子装反
Never checks the mirror. Sticks it in reverse.
一上高速路 就把她的脚从刹车上放下来
Puts her foot down, right out onto the highway.
天耶 这是赌博
Jeez Louise, that's gambling!
但是现在我在这 参加匿名戒赌小组
But here I am, Gamblers Anonymous.
你想说什么 鲍比
And your point is what, Bobby?
我的重点是 生活就是一场赌博 对吧
My point is this: Life's a gamble, right?
这是生活的激情所在
That's the thrill of it!
你们明白吗 你们大伙儿在这里
You know, you folks aren't here
不是因为你们是赌徒
because you're gamblers.
你们在这因为你们是差劲的赌徒
You are here because you are terrible gamblers.
好吧 让我们
Well, let's...
这就是问题所在 你输了 所以你来到了这里
That's the problem. You lose, and that's why you're here.
好吧 鲍比
Okay, Bobby...
我一直看着你们磨磨叽叽
I've been looking at you guys yammering on
说你们的破事
about all of your stuff and...
比如“都是我的错”或者“太糟了”
”..."Oh, woe is me" And "This is terrible."
但是你们知道问题在哪吗
But you know what the problem is?
问题在于你们缺少一样东西
The problem is you don't have a "Thing."
-能不能 -你们缺少一样东西
-Can we just... -They don't have a thing.
你们需要一个切入点 你们需要一个角度
They need an edge. You need an angle,
一个内部轨迹
an inside track, something...
能把你从赌徒变成骗子的东西
...that's gonna turn you from being a gambler to a hustler.
好了 鲍比 谢谢你
All right, Bobby, thank you.
从败者变为赢家
From a loser to a winner.
我们为什么要放弃
Why should we give up the one thing in life
我们的一生挚爱呢
that we really love?
这些朋友不需要停下他们所做的事
These folks don't need to stop what they're doing,
他们只是需要变得精通这件事
they just need to get better at it.
-好了 鲍比 求你了 -谁来做庄 谁下注
-Okay, Bobby, please. -Who's dealing? Who's in?
哈
Huh?
我心都碎了
I'm heartbroken.
我不知道她为什么不在半路来见我
I don't know why she won't meet me halfway.
这真的是个不合理的要求吗
I mean, is that too unreasonable to ask?
你有想过你可能是因为
Have you considered you might be
从错误的角度来考虑这件事吗
coming at this from the wrong angle?
每个角度 医生 我已经试过每个角度了 相信我
Every angle, Doc. I have tried every angle, believe me.
我们谈过这件事了
I know we've discussed this before.
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
你是大男子主义 她是大女子主义
You're an alpha male. She's an alpha female.
可能你需要面对现实了
Maybe you have to face the fact
对你来说她不是那个合适的女人
that she's just not the right woman for you.
不 我明白你的意思
Nah, I understand what you're saying...
但是比利·简是
...but Billie Jean would make
最合适的人选
the best match by a million miles.
她是这群女人的领导者 是门面
She is the leader of these women. The face.
看这比率 她在下个赛季都不可能做第一了
At this rate, she's not even gonna be Number 1 next season.
她不能吗
She's not?
不能 是玛格丽特·考特
Nope. Margaret Court.
真的吗 “铁臂女将”会是第一吗
Really? The Arm's gonna be Number 1?
哈
Huh.
翻还是不翻
Stick or twist?
翻
Twist.
红心杰克 不走运
Jack of Hearts. Too bad.
问题是 玛格丽特不光会成为第一
The point is, not only is Margaret gonna be Number 1...
她还是与比利不同的另一种女人
...but she's a different kind of woman.
你觉得她会耍我吗
You think she'd play me?
她是个温和守旧的女孩 鲍比
She's a nice old-fashioned girl, Bobby.
她会按别人教她的去做
She'll do as she's damn well told.
我昨晚不应该喝那么多
I shouldn't have had so much to drink last night.
这是不可原谅的
It's inexcusable.
你只喝了半杯酒
You had like half a drink.
半杯酒就够多了
Well... that's half a drink too many.
这周就是决赛了
It's the finals this week.
我的钥匙在哪
Where are my keys?
我觉得它们在你手里
I think they're in your hand.
谢谢你 好了
Thank you. Okay.
你现在该走了
You should leave now.
五分钟后我就跟上来
Then I'll follow in about five minutes.
好的
All right.
不过那样可能看上去更可疑
Or actually that will seem suspicious.
可能你待在这会更好
Maybe you should just stay here.
好吧
Okay.
你说过你会捎我一程的
You said you'd give me a ride.
对 对
Right. Right.
说的对 好了
Right on. Okay.
准备好了吗 东西都拿了吗
Ready to go? Got everything?
嗯
Yeah.
对不起 我刚刚只是有点
Sorry about that. I'm just a little...
小心那个模型 亨利
Be careful with that mannequin, Henry.
当然了 泰德
Of course, Ted.
哎哟 看看谁来了
Well, look what we have here.
迟到了
Late!
有点随随便便啊 你说对吧
And a little deshabille, wouldn't you say?
是啊 亨利 我也这么觉得
I would, Henry. I most definitely would.
你觉得赖瑞会怎么说
And what do you think Larry would say?
总得让他知道
He must know.
他总有一天
Well, there's knowing...
会知道的
...and there's knowing.
没人能迟过四点
Nobody later than four.
罗茜呢 罗茜在哪
Rosie? Where's Rosie?
我在这
I'm here.
别再被开超速罚单了 好吗
No more speeding tickets, okay?
这是网球赛 不是纳斯卡车赛
This is tennis, not NASCAR.
还有姑娘们 我求你们了 看在上帝的份上
And girls, I am begging you, for God's sake...
在照相的时候穿点紧身裤
some Slims at the photo call.
对我们有好处
They've been great to us,
我们还指着它们帮我们签新合同呢
and we need them to renew our contract.
我就喜欢穿 看看我
And I like it. I mean, look at me. Mmm.
对吧
Right?
你迟到了 还有这是谁
You're late. And who's that?
她吗 我的 我的朋友
This? My, uh, my friend.
洛杉矶那家沙龙的玛丽莲
Marilyn from the salon in L.A.
等等 她跟我们一起来巡回赛吗
Wait, is she coming on tour with us?
是个好主意
That's a great idea.
不不 她不来
Oh, no, she is not.
拜托了 格拉迪斯 我们有那么多照片要拍
Please, Gladys. With all the photo shoots we're doing,
我们需要一个发型师
we need a hairdresser.
答案是 不 行
That would be an N followed by an O.
这两个字怎么拼的 瓦尔
How's your spelling, Val?
不不不 她住在洛杉矶
No, no, no. She lives in L.A.
她工作的沙龙在洛杉矶
She works at the salon in L.A.
她不能跟我们一起上路
She can't just come on the road.
-拜托了 -没有 不行
-Come on. -It's not... No.
我只走几天他们是不会想我的
They're not gonna miss me for just a few days.
是啊 我们都可以付一点钱
Yeah. I mean, we could all pay a little bit.
是啊 求你了 格拉迪斯 看看我的头发
Yes, please, Gladys? Look at them!
它们挡住我的眼睛了 我都看不见球了
They get in my eyes. I can't see the ball.
求你了 老姐
Please, Mom?
求你了 我都没时间打理刘海了
Please, I've had no time to get these bangs done.
这个主意不错 老姐
It's a great idea, Mom.
想想你会有自己的发型
Imagine having your own stylist.
就一会儿
Just for a little while.
你能给我搞搞我的发型吗
Can you do anything with this?
当然可以了
Of course! Yeah.
上车吧
Ugh. Get in the car.
可以吗
Is this okay?
当然 当然 很棒啊
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, it's good.
你好啊
Hello.
你知道她是个什么吧 那个
You do know what she is, don't you? That...
跟比利·简一起的女人
...woman with Billie Jean?
发型师吗
Hairdresser?
我觉得那是她情人
I think it's her lover.
那个女孩
That girl?
和比利·简吗
And Billie Jean?
她结婚了
She's married.
她们都是这样
They usually are.
在一个全是女人的巡游里就会发生这种事 巴里
That's what happens on an all-women circuit, Barry.
放纵 伤风败俗
Licentiousness. Immorality.
罪恶
Sin.
真的吗 因为她不该跟着去巡回赛
Really? Because she shouldn't be allowed on tour.
正相反
On the contrary.
那她都不为自己感到羞耻吗
Well, isn't she ashamed of herself?
她是很羞耻 她就是
She is ashamed. That's exactly what she is.
她的把戏不会成功的
And her game's gonna fall to pieces.
昨晚的事不能再发生了
What happened last night can't happen again.
我们不能再这么玩下去了
We have to stop fooling around.
我没有玩 我很认真的
I wasn't fooling around. I was dead serious.
听着
Listen.
赖瑞都不能跟我一起来巡回赛
Larry doesn't even come on tour with me,
因为我不能分心
because I can't have the distraction.
我必须百分百集中在我的比赛上
I have to focus on my game a hundred percent.
我保证不会让你分心
I promise not to distract you.
但是你确实让我分心了
But you do distract me.
你光是在这里就让我分心了
You distract me just being here.
你到底是何方妖孽
Who are you?
你对我做了什么
What are you doing with me?
我是玛丽莲·凯瑟琳·巴尼特
I'm Marilyn Kathryn Barnett.
我有一双灵巧的手
I'm good with my hands.
我不喜欢听从指示
I don't like being told what to do.
而我刚遇见了生命中最有趣的人
And I just met the most interesting person.
我没有那么有趣 我保证
I'm not that interesting. I promise.
我现在想的只有网球
All I think about is tennis.
我们不需要做任何你不想做的事 好吗
We don't have to do anything you don't want to do. Okay?
做朋友吗
Friends?
-好 -好闺蜜吗
-Okay. -Really good friends?
好
Okay.
我发誓 在你身边我就不知所措了
I swear, I don't know what to do with myself around you.
开车就好
Just drive.
我知道 嘘
I know. Shh.
鲍比
Bobby.
巴利 好久不见 你好吗
Barry, how you doing? Been a long time. How are you?
你来干什么
What do you want?
我待五分钟就走
Five minutes is all.
我要说的话你如果不想听
And if you don't like what I have to say,
我就再也不说了
you'll never hear from me again.
-此话当真 -让他进来吧
-Is that a promise? -Let him in.
你好吗 玛格丽特
Hey, Margaret, how are you?
你最好说点有意义的事情
This better be good.
我们忙得连睡觉的时间都没有
No one's getting a lot of sleep around here.
那当然 肯定是有意义的事情
Oh, it's good! It's good.
-他叫什么 -丹尼尔
-Who's this? -That's Daniel.
丹尼尔 介意给我抱一下吗
Daniel! Do you mind?
-我可以吗 -可以
-May I? -Yeah.
丹尼尔 来我怀里 好个大胖小子
Oh, Daniel, come here, you. Oh, you're so big!
丹尼尔 你好呀
Oh, Daniel, hello!
鲍比我抱着你呢
Bobby's gotcha. Bobby's gotcha.
是我 瞧瞧你
Yeah, that's right. Oh, look at you.
玛格丽特 他太可爱了
Oh, Margaret, he is lovely.
你好呀 队里有其他女的生孩子了吗
Hi! Do any of the other girls have kids?
没有 只有我一个
Nope, just me.
只有你生了孩子 天啊
Just you. Wow!
那肯定很不容易 你妈妈不容易啊
That has got to be tough. Tough on your mom.
全天都要训练
Playing all day and then taking care
SSK字幕组
晚上还得照顾你 小伙子
of you at night. Oh, boy!
SSK字幕组
那肯定很 而且还要四处跑来跑去
That's got to be... And all the traveling?
你知道吗 你需要请个保姆
You know what? You need a nanny.
-保姆 -你知道请保姆要花多少钱吗
-A nanny. -You know how much they cost?
我来就是为了这个
That's exactly why I'm here.
三万五千美金可以让你请很多个保姆
Because I think $35,000 would buy you a lot of nanny.
你葫芦里卖什么药 鲍比·里格斯
What is your game, Bobby Riggs?
你和我来一场比赛
A match. You versus me.
三盘两胜 你就能拿到三万五千美金
Two out of three sets. $35,000.
为什么选我
Well... why me?
为什么选你 因为你是最厉害的
Why you? Because you're the best.
我一直想找比利·简对打
Billie Jean has been on me to play her,
但你知道她的为人
but you know what she's like.
我知道
Yeah.
除此之外 我经常说 你要是决定上场
And besides, I always say if you're gonna play...
就要和冠军对打
...play the number one.
比利·简是冠军
Billie Jean's number one.
明天你打败她之后 她就不是了
Not if you beat her tomorrow.
对吗 你妈妈能打赢她吗
Isn't that right? Is your mom gonna beat her?
第四十个单词 纵向 伐木工具
40 down. "Lumberjack's tool."
由四个字母组成
Four letters.
有想到什么吗
Anything?
-我去 -怎么了
-Oh, my. -What?
-赖瑞来了 -什么
-It's Larry. -Hmm?
赖瑞·金
Larry King.
我
Oh.
去
我得打个电话
I think I'd better make a phone call.
你好
Hello?
我是泰德 亲爱的 有个小帅哥要上楼了
Ted here, darling. A petite heads up.
赖瑞来了
Larry is in the building.
-卧槽 -小心点
-Shit. -Be careful.
好的 谢谢提醒
Okay. Thanks.
-你好 -噢
-Hey. -Oh.
-上楼去吗 -谢谢
-Going up? -Thanks.
是的 去三十一楼
Yeah. 31.
我也是
Me, too.
一大早就喝酒啊
Starting early.
众所周知
Oh, well, you know what they say...
什么时候喝香槟都不嫌早
it's never too early for champagne.
是我的菜
My kinda girl.
你来看网球赛的吗
You here for the tennis?
当然了
I sure am.
我也是
Me, too.
我觉得比利·简会赢
I think Billie Jean's gonna take it.
你是她的球迷吗
Oh, are you a fan?
算是吧
You could say that.
你先请
After you.
回见
Well, see you around.
好的
Maybe.
嗨 噢
Hi! Oh.
嗨
Hi.
-嗨 -嗨 亲爱的
-Hi! -Hi, honey.
这是玛丽莲
Oh, this is Marilyn.
噢
Oh.
-赖瑞 -嗨
-Larry. -Oh, hi, hi.
玛丽莲是
Marilyn is the, the...
发型师
The hairdresser around here.
赖瑞是我的
And... Larry is... the...
丈夫
The husband around here.
你的丈夫
我得帮比奇斯吹头发
Peaches wants me to give her a blow dry.
好的
Great.
-玛丽莲 -嗯
-Marilyn! -Uh-huh?
那桶冰是给比利·简敷膝盖的吗
Was the ice for Billie Jean's knees?
是的
Yeah.
-好的 给我吧 谢谢 -再见
-Yeah, I'll get that. Thanks. -Bye.
再见
Bye.
给我吧 我来弄
Here. Let me.
好
Okay.
外面不堵 所以我很快就到这里了
The roads were clear, so I made good time.
我应该先打电话给你
I should've called ahead,
告诉你我要来的
letting you know that I was coming.
把腿抬起来
Leg up.
换一只脚
Switch.
这里
Here.
呃
Uh...
我开多一间房
I'm gonna get another room.
还有电话要打
I've got phone calls to make,
你得为决赛做休整
and you need to rest for the finals.
考特女士得分 零比十五
Point to Mrs. Court. Love-15.
零比三十
Love-30.
天啊 比利
Jesus Christ, Billie.
加油啊 蠢货 加油
Come on, dumby. Come on.
零比四十 比赛赛点
Love-40. Match point.
比赛结束 获胜者是考特女士
Game, set and match to Mrs. Court.
我太丢人了
That was bad.
你看起来不在状态
You don't seem yourself.
我想回家了
I was thinking of heading home.
真的吗
Really?
有好多事情要做 而且
There's lots to do from there and...
我想
...I was thinking...
给你点空间 好让你理一理头绪
...I could give you some space and let you clear your head.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
-晚点见 -好
-Talk to you soon. -Yeah.
呃
Man.
我去
Damn.
嗨
Hi.
你有烟吗
Have you got a cigarette?
没有
Nope.
比利·简知道你吸烟吗
Billie Jean know you smoke?
呃 应该不知道
Uh... I guess not.
她不喜欢别人抽烟
She's not a fan.
你不说我不说 就没人知道
Well, I won't tell if you won't.
秘密是吧 这还有不少呢
Secrets, huh? There's a lot of those going around.
玛丽莲 你知道这些钱哪里来的吗
Marilyn, you know how all this gets paid for?
比如
Yeah, the...
获胜奖金 球拍 酒店 机票
...the prize money, rackets, hotels, flights...
食物 全部东西
...the food, everything?
都来自赞助商
Sponsorship.
而在赞助商的眼皮底下 如果有的事情被公之于众
And with sponsorship, that would go away in a heartbeat
钱就会打水漂
if certain things were to be made public.
我心里只为比利·简着想
I only have Billie Jean's best interests at heart.
瞧你
Look.
你是个好女孩
You seem like a sweet girl and...
别拍我马屁
Don't condescend to me.
求你了
Please.
我们这又不是在比赛
You know, I'm not the competition.
我只是她的丈夫 而你
I'm just her husband, and you're...
你只是一个过渡
...you're just a phase.
我们都只是来助兴的
We're both just sideshows.
网球才是她的真爱
Tennis is her true love.
如果你想在她和比赛中间插足 你就会出局
And if you get between her and the game, you'll be gone.
昨晚我和鲍比·里格斯见面了
Met Bobby Riggs last night.
他很风趣
Funny man.
告诉我你没这么做
Tell me you didn't.
没怎么做
Didn't what?
他只是想来一场表演赛
He just wants to play an exhibition match is all.
既然我已经是冠军了
Now that I'm officially number one.
这不是一场真正的网球比赛 玛格丽特 你知道的
It's not a tennis match, Margaret. You do know that.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
他也跟我说过这个表演赛的事情
He tried that exhibition match line on me.
是嘛 我猜你拒绝他了
Oh. And I suppose you turned him down?
你在开玩笑么
Are you kidding me?
你觉得我会跟鲍比·里格斯一起演猴戏吗
You think I want to join the Bobby Riggs circus?
他想让自己出名 让女人出糗
He wants to make himself look great and women look stupid.
那不是比赛 而是一场秀
It's not a match. It's a show.
我明白你不跟他对打的原因 但是
I can understand why you might not want to play him, but...
我可没有什么要藏着掖着
...I've got nothing to hide.
-脱衣服的时候 小心别把衣服撑裂了 -你听到了吧
-Mind those seams when you're taking that off. -You hear that?
她要对阵鲍比·里格斯
She's gonna play Bobby Riggs.
铁臂对阵烂嘴 我知道这局该押谁
The Arm versus The Mouth. I know where my money's going.
她要是输了怎么办 泰德 要是输了呢
What if she loses, Ted? What if she blows it?
他不会善罢甘休的
He's never gonna let it go.
他会让女子网球沦为笑柄
He's gonna make women's tennis look like a laughingstock.
淡定点 大明星
Calm yourself, Madame Superstar.
如今的玛格丽特所向披靡
Margaret is playing better than ever,
这一点不用我提醒你
and I don't need to remind you.
以下对话 只能你知我知
And strictly entre nous...
你袖子的尺寸 我们得做一些调整
...we've had to make some adjustments in the bicep area.
对吗 亨利
Haven't we, Henry?
大概要改宽一点五英寸
About an inch and a half.
你不跟他对打 我很高兴
I'm just glad you're not playing him.
下辈子吧
Not a chance.
你最好小心点
Best be careful.
这话什么意思
What do you mean?
世人没你想象的那么宽容 亲爱的
The world isn't always a forgiving place, my dear.
你怎么总能那么自由自在
How are you so free with yourself?
看起来你想做什么就做什么
Seems like you just do whatever you want.
我没有
I don't do whatever I want.
我也要交税 看牙医
I pay taxes, visit the dentist.
你知道我不是在说这个
You know what I mean.
我只是八个兄弟姐妹中的一个
I'm one of eight kids.
所以
So...
没人有空搭理我
...no one noticed what I did.
可能这是个好事
Which is probably for the best,
因为我本来应该吓死他们
because I would've shocked the hell out of all of 'em.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我的生活很私密
I live... A private life...
而且
...and...
我从不认为大家会关注我的一举一动
...I guess I never think that people will care what I do.
天 大家可都盯着我的一举一动呢
God, I think everyone cares what I do.
我会让他们所有人失望
I'm gonna let them all down.
小时候 我在网球俱乐部打比赛
When I was a kid, I played at this tennis club.
我当时
I was...
十二岁
...twelve.
那时我们团队合照 很隆重
It was team photo time, which is a very big deal.
我母亲给我做了
And my mom made me these...
白色运动短裤
...white tennis shorts,
因为我们买不起网球裙
because we couldn't afford a tennis dress.
然后
And...
经营俱乐部的男老板
...the man that ran it,
我们排好队形准备拍照
we were all lined up to take the photo
他指着我说
and he pointed at me and he said...
“那个小女孩不能出现在合照里”
..."That little girl cannot be in the photo...
“因为她没有穿网球裙”
..."because she's not wearing a tennis dress."
那肯定很伤人
That must've crushed you.
没有
No.
我只是在想
I just thought...
就这样了
...that does it.
我要成为最厉害的选手
I'm gonna be the best.
这样一来 我才有能力改变一些事情
That way I can really... change things.
我才有话语权
That way I have a voice.
你做到了
You have a voice.
-爸爸 -拉里
-Dad? -Larry!
抱歉我没办法待久 我还在训练
Sorry I can't stay long. I'm training.
你穿的是什么鬼
What the hell are you wearing?
这是桑拿服
Ah. It's a sauna suit.
穿这衣服要我的命 但每呼吸一次
It's killing me, but every time I breathe,
我就会掉一磅体重
I lose a pound.
你听说了吗 鲍比回归了
You hear the news? Bobby's back!
是的 我听说了
Yeah, yeah, I heard.
你知道了 是不是觉得很棒
You heard, huh? Isn't it great?
是真的吗
Is it really happening?
是的 这是真的 说吧
Oh, it's happening. It is happening! Say...
-你愿不愿意帮我 -帮你什么
-You want to help? -What with?
帮我什么 帮我训练 给我支持
What with? With training, with support.
跟你老爹打几局网球
Hit some balls for your old man.
罗尼来了
Lornie's coming in.
我不懂了 为什么是我
I don't know. Why me?
为什么 因为你是我的儿子
Why you? You're my son, that's why.
我们一起努力 来吧
Do this thing together. Come on!
里格斯家的男人向世界宣战
The Riggs boys against the world!
-你觉得你能打败她吗 -噢
-You think you can beat her? -Oh.
和玛格丽特的这件事只是个开头
This Margaret thing is just the beginning.
接下来要搞大事情
It's gonna be huge.
三次温网冠军
Three-time Wimbledon Champion,
四次美国女子单打
four times Women's Single Champion
冠军获得者
in the United States...
网球比赛大满贯
...winner of the Grand Slam of tennis,
目前女子专业组巡回赛的
and current leading money winner
最高奖金获得者
of the Women's Pro Tour.
欢迎来自澳洲的玛格丽特·考特
From Australia, meet Margaret Court.
她的对手是
Her opponent...
两次美国网球单打冠军获得者
...twice the United States Singles Champion,
同时也是温网冠军
also a winner at Wimbledon.
1967年被载入网球名人堂的
A man who in 1967 was enshrined
男子选手
into the Tennis Hall of Fame.
语不惊人死不休 颇受争议的 鲍比·里格斯
Colorful and controversial Bobby Riggs.
你押谁赢 杰克 男选手还是女选手
Who's your money on, Jack? Mankind or womankind?
毋庸置疑 当然是鲍比·瑞格斯
Bobby Riggs, without a doubt.
玛格丽特·考特是一名出色的网球运动员
Margaret Court is a great tennis player,
这不用说 但是
there's no mistake about that, but the...
女人的天性决定了她们没办法
...thing about women is that they find it hard
持续地承受压力
to consistently handle the pressure.
有人说 她们天生不是这块料
Some would say they're not built for it.
抱歉让一让
Excuse me!
比赛已经开始了
It's started already!
维珍妮来了
Virginia Slims coming through!
电视机在哪里
Where are the TVs?
快点 赶紧的 亨利
Quickly! Come on, Henry.
我们不想错过比赛
We don't want to miss this.
大家安静点
Everybody, shut up!
最后一个洗衣服用的硬币了
That's the last of our laundry quarters.
在哪个频道
It's on what channel?
大家都安静点好吗
Can we have some quiet here?
-拜托了 -在哪个频道 第四台吗
-Please? -Where, on four?
是的 第四台
Yeah, it's four.
噢 看到了
Oh! There we are.
我的天 场面很隆重
Oh, my God. This is big.
当然了 那可是鲍比
Of course it's big. It's Bobby.
这男人只剩下浮夸了
The one thing that man can do is hustle.
可不是嘛
I'll say.
鲍比·里格斯还有两球
Bobby Riggs is two games away
就能赢得第一盘的比赛
from winning this first set.
易如反掌
Rather easily, I might add.
我的天
Oh, my God.
玛格丽特可能没意识到自己面前是怎样的对手
Margaret may not realize what she's up against.
本来我们应该到现场支持她
I think we should have been there to support her.
你还有锦标赛要打
You have a tournament to play.
我是你的经纪人 别忘了 比奇斯
I own you, Peaches, don't forget that.
低级失误
What a dreadful choice of blue!
天啊
Oh, God.
如果她不主动进攻
If she doesn't start attacking the ball,
她就会掉进他的圈套里
she's gonna fall into his trap.
她脸色苍白
She looks spooked.
这件裙子怎么样
Do we like the dress?
是泰德做的 我们有说不的权利吗
It's one of Ted's. Are we allowed not to?
我就在你身后呢 亲爱的
Right behind you, darling.
我们爱死这件裙子了
We love the dress!
-谢谢 -很好看
-Thank you. -It's great.
希望玛格丽特
I'm just hoping that Margaret
能开始进攻对方
will really start hitting the ball
争取发球得分
and follow her serve to the net.
她一直顾着防守是没办法赢得比赛的
I don't see how she can win staying back.
场面看起来就像是鲍比在逗她玩
It looks like Bobby's just toying with her.
如果玛格丽特也认为他在胡闹
That's gonna have a demoralizing
她自己的斗志
effect on Margaret
将会大受影响
if she thinks he's just horsing around.
-噢天啦 -事实如此
-Oh, dear. -Let's face it.
她对付不了鲍比的把戏
She just can't handle Bobby's game.
加油
Come on!
很好
Nice one.
太棒了
Bravo!
“铁臂”肯定行的
The Arm'll be fine.
她胳膊一挥 就能
She could squeeze the life out of that
打得那讨厌鬼找不着北
little twerp with one tweak of her bicep.
四十比零
40-love.
不 玛格丽特
No, Margaret.
振作起来 玛格丽特
Wake up, Margaret!
我不喜欢这个样子
I'm not liking this.
格拉迪斯 我要去抽支烟
Gladys, I think I'm gonna need a cigarette.
我的姑娘们终于有人抽烟了
Finally, one of my girls smokes!
里格斯先生拿下了这一局
Game to Mr. Riggs.
盘分是里格斯先生一比零
Mr. Riggs leads one set to nothing.
鲍比·里格斯的所有
There's not a single thing
我都极度讨厌
I don't hate about Bobby Riggs,
所有
not a single thing.
鲍比·里格斯进入第二盘比赛
Bobby Riggs here in the second set.
里格斯得分
Riggs does it again.
鲍比今天势不可挡
Bobby's unstoppable today.
鲍比·里格斯得分
Bobby Riggs.
鲍比·里格斯再得分
Again, Bobby Riggs.
玛格丽特看上去无心恋战
Margaret seems to be off her game.
我敢肯定
I'll say!
四十比零 精彩
40-love. Beautiful.
了不起
This is awful.
里格斯赢得本局
Game to Mr. Riggs.
惨不忍睹
Really terrible.
鲍比·里格斯再得分
Again, Bobby Riggs.
亨利 咱们再来杯鸡尾酒
Let's get another cocktail, Henry.
嗯 我以前就说过
Well, as I said...
女人并非不能打网球
...it's not that women can't play tennis,
但她们无法承受压力
it's just that they can't deal with the pressure.
也许这场比赛可以彻底破灭女选手们
Perhaps this will finally put a stop to women players
奖金要向男人们看齐的梦想
demanding the same prize money as men.
我们今天看到 他们完全
As we've seen today, they're simply...
不在同一级别
not in the same league.
这就是事实 不管女人想怎么样
Let's face it, in business,
但在商业 政治 体育
politics, sports, you name it...
你随便说哪个领域
...whatever they like to think,
到最后 处在最顶端的 都是男人
at the very top it's a man's game.
难以置信
I can't believe this.
我知道怎么让她振作
I know what'll cheer her up.
-我马上回来 -好的
-I'll be right back. -Okay, darling.
现在是赛点
We're at match point here.
比赛结束了 鲍比·里格斯胜 六比零 六比一
There it is. Bobby Riggs wins 6-2, 6-1.
真难以置信
Unbelievable.
轻而易举地战胜了
A rather easy triumph against
母亲和妇女解放运动
motherhood and women's liberation.
简直是屠杀
That was a massacre.
恭喜你 鲍比
Congratulations, Bobby.
非常感谢
Well, thank you very much.
这是我儿子拉里
This is my son, Larry.
球技差 人很好
Lousy tennis player, great guy.
鲍比·里格斯现在正式成为
So, now officially Bobby Riggs
世界头号女子网球选手
is the number one ladies player in the world...
在那看比赛的任何女士
...and any ladies out there
想挑战我这项桂冠的
want to challenge for the crown,
你知道怎么联系我
you know where to find me.
今天 我顶着某些人的怀疑
And since I have just proven here today,
在此证明了
beyond a shadow of a doubt...
男人是更高等的动物
...that men are the superior animal,
所以我宣布
tell you want I'm gonna do:
把奖金提高三倍
I am gonna triple the bet!
奖励十万美元给任何打败鲍比·里格斯的女士
$100,000 to any woman who can beat Bobby Riggs.
不过我问自己 真的有这个人吗
The question I ask myself is, is she out there,
就算有 她有这个胆吗
and does she have the nerve?
她受了什么刺激
What got into her?
命运 亲爱的
Fate, sweetie.
像脱轨的列车 向她猛冲过来
Coming at her like a runaway train.
哦 亲爱的
Oh... darling.
今天广为传播的
And in today's much publicized
一场网球比赛
tennis face-off between...
由资深职业选手鲍比·里格斯
...Senior Pro Bobby Riggs
对阵女网头号选手玛格丽特·考特
and Woman's No. 1 Margaret Court...
自诩为“男性沙文主义猪”的里格斯
...the self-styled "Male chauvinist pig"
直落两盘以六比二 六比一击败了考特女士
beat Mrs. Court in straight sets, 6-2, 6-1...
报道称之为
...in what the press has dubbed
“母亲节的屠杀”
"The Mother's Day Massac..."
噢天 不过是一场网球比赛而已
Oh, for goodness sakes. It was just a tennis match.
女网一号打不赢55岁老汉
The Women's No. 1 can't beat a 55-year-old.
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
他逼得我没有退路
He's backed me into a corner now.
那就不跟他比
Then don't play him.
玛丽莲 还有谁能打败他
Who else is gonna beat him, Marilyn?
我没别的选择
I don't have a choice.
不 你一直都有别的选择
No, you always have a choice.
你不明白
You don't get it.
我不知道怎么能帮到你
I don't know how to help you.
你还想我留在这儿吗
Do you even want me here?
我不知道 很抱歉 我要想想
I don't know. I'm sorry. I need to think.
喂
Hello?
赖瑞
Larry.
噢 我正在想你什么时候打电话来
Oh. I was wondering when you were gonna call.
他在出丑弄怪
It was a travesty.
然后呢
So?
打给那笨蛋
Call the bozo.
跟他说我跟他比赛
Tell him it's on.
但是没有我的同意
But nothing gets agreed on
不能跟他敲定细节 好吗
without my approval, all right?
地点 时间 电视转播权 所有事
Venue, date, TV rights, everything.
包括比赛用球
What balls we use.
我了解鲍比 目前为止他都是让自己的赢面最大化
I know Bobby. He'll be making deals on his deals by now.
明天一早我就打给他
I'll call him first thing in the morning.
不 现在就打 他上次也是半夜三更打给我
No, now. He calls me at midnight.
既然我们决定干 那就开始
If we're gonna go, let's go.
好
Okay.
我想说
You know something?
这事了不起
This can be great.
真的 真的了不起
Really, really great.
而且不仅仅是为了女子网球运动
And not just for women's tennis, you know?
前提是必须赢
As long as I win.
如果说我对你还有所了解的话
If there's one thing that I know about you...
那就是这场比赛 你一定会赢
...it's that this is one match you are gonna win.
赖瑞 你是个好男人
You're a good man, Larry.
你也是个好女人
You're a good woman.
但愿我是
I wish that were true.
集中精力打好比赛 其他事先放一边
Let's focus on the match. Everything else can wait.
晚安
Good night.
玛丽莲
Marilyn?
宝贝 我重回巅峰了
Honey! I am back on top,
从没觉得这么爽 我打败了玛格丽特·考特
I've never felt better, I beat Margaret Court...
现在又要去打比利·简·金
...and now I am playing Billie Jean King
奖金十万美元 怎么样
for $100,000. What about that?
而且
And...
ABC电视黄金时段转播
...it's going to be on ABC, primetime.
嗯 你脸皮挺厚
Well, you have some nerve using all that
敢用“男性沙文主义猪”这种屁话
"Male chauvinist pig" Nonsense.
你觉得这么多年一直是谁在养你
Who do you think's been bankrolling
是我 一个女人
you all these years? Me. A woman.
要我说吧 你说得太对了
You know something? You are absolutely right,
我要还钱给你
and I am gonna pay you back.
-噢真的吗 -真的
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
我不要你还钱
I don't want it back.
那把我还给你好吗
You want me back?
现在
So...
我就要等上《时代周刊》的封面
...I'm gonna be on the cover of Time magazine.
我虽然拿过三次温网冠军
I won the triple at Wimbledon
但还从没上过《时代》的封面
and never got the cover of Time.
打败比利·简·金以后 有人公开提出
So after Billie Jean, there's an offer on the table
奖励一百万美元 要我打格丽斯·埃弗特
for a million dollars to play Chrissie Evert.
一百万美元哪
A million dollars, huh!
想一想
Imagine that?
一百万
Million dollars.
嗯
Phew.
我跟你说
I'll tell you something.
我现在走的这条路 还是很惊险的
It's a pretty scary trip I'm taking right here...
而且
...and, uh...
这个 我
...well, I was, um...
我需要你 宝贝
Well, I need you, honey.
我怎么觉得 这一出我们以前就经历过
I feel like we've been through this before.
不 我已经变了 你去问精神科医生
No, I'm a changed man. Ask the shrink.
我去了
I did.
他怎么说
What did he say?
啥也没说 不过他给了我三十美元
Nothing. He just gave me 30 bucks.
是上次跟你玩二十一点时
The money that he owed you
欠你的赌债
from your last game of blackjack.
他水平太烂了
He was a terrible player.
天
Christ.
鲍比 我爱你
Bobby, I love you.
我也爱你
Well, I love you, too.
我爱你逗我大笑
I love how you make me laugh.
我爱你那些疯点子和诡计
I love your crazy ideas and all your schemes.
还有你一进房间就满屋生动的力量
And the way you walk into a room and you fill it up.
我爱你引我去感受的方式
I love the way you make me feel.
我非常怀念这些
I miss that a lot.
但是
But...
我需要的是丈夫
...I need a husband.
我需要一个踏实的人
I need someone who is steady.
一个我可以依靠的人
Someone that I can rely on.
而你却不是那样的人
And that is not you.
这也没什么
And that's okay.
不 不是没什么
It is more than okay.
其实是精彩绝伦 因为
It is wonderful, because that...
你的个性如此
...is who you are.
但我不能再跟这样的人一起过了
I just can't be with that person anymore.
就是不能
I just can't.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不
No.
是我对不起你
I'm sorry.
好
Okay.
好吧
All right.
嗯
Okay.
再见
Good-bye.
嗨 吉米 我是鲍比 你怎么样啊 老友
Hey, Jimmy! Bobby here. How are you, my friend?
再好不过 再好不过
Never better, never better.
现在是什么赔率
Listen, what are the odds right now?
好 我押一万五千美元到我自己赢
Okay, put 15 grand on me to win.
没错老友 一万五
That's right, buddy, 15 big ones.
好极了 再见
Okay. Great. Thank you, sir.
下面播报其他新闻
In other news, another battle
没有止境的性别之战再燃战火
in the never-ending war of the sexes...
这次是在网球场上
...this one on the tennis court
奖金高达十万美元
for a $100,000 purse.
今天公布消息
It was announced today.
女网冠军
Women's tennis champion
29岁的比利·简·金小姐
Miss Billie Jean King, who is 29...
接受了55岁的鲍比·里格斯的挑战
...accepted the challenge of 55-year-old Bobby Riggs...
比赛时间
...the match to be held at a time
和地点暂未决定
and place still to be decided.
金小姐表示 她来比赛并非为钱
Miss King said she will not play
而是 用她的原话
for the money but, in her words...
“为了恢复女网运动
..."to put women's tennis
和妇女解放运动应有的地位”
"And women's lib back where it belongs."
里格斯则说 他之所以发出挑战是因为
Riggs said he issued the challenge because...
“我想证明女人低能
..."I want to prove that women are lousy
她们不配与男人同场竞技”
"And they don't belong on the same court as a man."
喔
Wow.
-放那里 -好 很好
-Put her there. -All right, great.
不要误解我的意思 我爱女人
Now, don't get me wrong, I love women...
在床上和厨房里的女人
In the bedroom and in the kitchen.
但是这些日子 她们却想到处跑
But these days, they want to be everywhere!
什么事都想干
They want to be doing everything!
这还有完没完
Where is it gonna end?
很快我们男人就会没法打棒球
Pretty soon us fellas won't be able to go to a ballgame,
没法去钓鱼
we won't be able to go fishing.
没法下班后去喝一杯
We won't be able to stop and have a drink after work.
这就是整个妇女解放运动的所谓意义
And that's what this whole women's lib thing is about.
这一切必须停止
And it's got to stop.
鲍比·里格斯就是那个制止它的男人
And Bobby Riggs is the man to stop it.
女士们先生们 这就是卡斯特的最后防线
Ladies and gentlemen, this is Custer's Last Stand.
这是网球高手和女权论者的战争
This is the Lobber versus the Libber!
明白了吗
Take that. Right?
接着说 鲍比
Keep talking, Bobby.
你满嘴胡话越多
The more nonsense you spout,
输的时候越难看
the worse it will be when you lose.
这个嘛 我是女网一号
Well, I'm the ladies number one,
是冠军 我怎么会输
I'm the champ. Why would I lose?
因为老化石不会打网球
Because dinosaurs can't play tennis.
我要把这场“秀”放到“沙文主义”里
I'm gonna put the "Show" Back in "Chauvinism."
先生们
Gentlemen.
多美的天 真适合打网球 是不是
What a beautiful day to play tennis, huh?
好 打这里 就在柱子下
All right, right here. Right down the pike.
好 我来了
All right, I'm coming in.
我来了 给个高球
I'm coming in! Give me a lob!
对吧 就得这么打
Right? That's how you do it.
知道我在干啥吗 做饭
You know what I'm doing? I'm cooking.
我在做饭 像不像
I'm cooking! Am I cooking?
噢
Oh...
噢 看我的
Oh, there we go!
啊
Ah!
没问题 我接到了
All right, I got it.
她们直接进来 我送她们回家
They walked right into it. I'm taking 'em all home!
她们要为我洗衣服
They're gonna do my laundry.
知道这是什么感觉吗 就像转世一样
You know what it's like? Being reincarnated.
这是我做过最了不起的事
It's the greatest thing I've ever done.
比赢得温网还牛
It's bigger than winning Wimbledon,
牛过森林山 牛过巡回赛
bigger than Forest Hills, bigger than the Pro Tour.
我职业生涯中的高点 说不定是我一生的高点
High point of my career, maybe my life.
嗨 宝贝 来一杯怎么样
Hey, sweetie, how about a cocktail?
来
There we go.
噢小心 我差点弄折了你胳膊
Oh, watch it! I almost took your arms off.
我不是说
I'm not saying that women
女人不属于网球场
don't belong on the court.
我的意思是 那个 不然谁来捡球啊
I mean, heck, who would pick up the balls otherwise?
但是这么多叫嚣平等的
But all of this shouting and yammering about equality.
这要平等 那也要平等
Equality this, equality that.
喂 给鲍比·里格斯来点平等怎么样
Hey, how about some equality for Bobby Riggs?
今天我这是第三次全裸了
This is my third nude shoot today.
我就是一老头 努力想维持
I'm this old guy, trying to make ends meet
上等生活 收入却很低
on the senior circuit, getting paid peanuts.
不过如果我打败女士们
But if I can beat the ladies
获得平等的奖金 多谢了
and get equal prize money, thank you very much...
那么 所有的女孩子都可以
...well, then all the girls can just head back
回去厨房了 那是她们的归属
in the kitchen where they belong.
瞧 他可以信口开河
Look, he can talk all he likes.
他也就这么点擅长的东西了
That's one of the few things he's good at.
但最重要的 是谁赢得比赛
But the only thing that matters is who wins the match.
鲍比
Bobby!
鲍比 我们来打网球
Bobby, let's play some tennis, man!
我去 是爸爸
Damn it, Dad.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-爸爸 -嗨 儿子
-Dad. -Hey, kiddo!
还以为我们来训练的
I thought we were practicing.
对此我只能说
You know what I have to say to that?
打玛格丽特·考特 六比二和六比一
Margaret Court. 6-2, 6-1.
我不需要训练 我有秘密武器
I don't need to practice, I got a secret weapon.
雷奥·布莱尔 我来介绍我一生中
Rheo Blair, I'd like you to meet the most
最重要的人 除我自己以外
important person in my life... apart from me.
我儿子 拉里
My son, Larry.
雷奥 你告诉他
You tell him, Rheo.
拉里 两个词 超级营养品
Two words, Larry: Super Nutrition.
超级营养品
Super Nutrition!
这些都是你吃的
You taking all of these?
一天四百粒
Four hundred a day!
你在开玩笑
You're kidding.
是的 我是有点话多
Yeah, I'm rattling around a little bit,
但是你得知道 我感觉比以前都好
but you know what? I feel better than ever.
它含有A到Z型氨基酸
It's the A to Z of amino acids.
还有维生素 蛋白质药片 燃脂药
Vitamins, protein pills, some fat busters,
以及雷奥的秘制药
and some of Rheo's Specials.
里面有什么
What's in those?
特别配方
Specialness.
Specialness!
谁需要训练 我要长生不老了
Who needs to train? I'm gonna live forever.
但是 我不知道
Yeah, but this, I don't know...
你能放松点吗
Oh, would you just relax? Come on.
你看了我是怎么赢玛格丽特的
You saw what I did to Margaret,
而她打败了比利·简
and she beat Billie Jean.
消灭了一个
One down!
下一个是什么
What's next?
她打得像个笨蛋
She played like an idiot.
没有可比性 玛格丽特根本不在状态
There's no comparison. Margaret folds.
你了解比利 她喜欢压力
You know Billie. She loves pressure.
但她现在风头正衰
Yeah, but her game's off right now.
是的 我讨厌这么说
It is. I mean, I hate to say it,
但我赌鲍比赢
but my money's on Bobby.
对 我也是
Yep. Mine, too.
钱可是比利·简帮忙挣来的
Money that you have because of Billie Jean.
没有个人恩怨 我并不想让他赢
It's not personal. I don't want him to win.
我只是认为他赢面大
I just think he will.
如果一定要下注
I think that if I had to bet money,
我押鲍比·里格斯赢
I would bet on Bobby Riggs.
我赌鲍比·里格斯赢
Well, my money's on Bobby Riggs.
我跟他同场竞技过
I've played with him.
这个男人有丰富的经验
The man has tremendous experience...
而且男性肌肉总是
...and the male muscle is always a little
比女性肌肉更强壮些
stronger than the female muscle.
比利·简·金
Billie Jean King.
你会想看的
You're gonna want to see this.
什么 我上电视了吗
What? Am I on?
你得来看看
You got to check this out.
比利·简·金是名出色的选手
Billie Jean King is an excellent player.
除此之外 我觉得她是一位美丽的女士
I think that besides that, she's a beautiful lady.
我喜欢美女
And I like beautiful ladies.
我看了鲍比打败玛格丽特的比赛
I saw Bobby beat Margaret,
他是名相当厉害的选手
and I think that he's a really tough player.
我认为他比比利·简更有优势
So I'd have to give him the edge over Billie Jean.
我喜欢
I like it.
森林山网球赛实时新闻
The breaking news from Forest Hills
比利·简·金
is that Billie Jean King...
在第三轮对阵朱莉·黑尔德曼的
...has defaulted in her third-round match
比赛中弃权
against Julie Heldman.
疲态尽显 士气皆无
Looking tired and dispirited,
金只打了一盘就离开了赛场
Mrs. King left the court after only one set.
有传言称
Speculation mounts that pressure from
即将对阵鲍比·里格斯
the upcoming match against Bobby Riggs...
让她倍感压力
...is taking its toll.
倍感压力 我就知道
Taking its toll, baby! I knew it!
她快崩溃了 我到游泳池去玩一会儿
She's crumbling, and I'm hanging out by the pool!
你忽悠我是想有更多时间训练吗
Are you scamming me to get more practice time?
我病了
I'm sick.
让我看看
Let me see that.
还死不了
Well, you're not dying.
你说得好听点不行吗
Try to sound pleased.
我也爱其他女孩
Look, I love the other girls, but...
但你是焦点 你是我的大明星
...you're the draw. You're my giant.
得了流感的大明星 我也不知道该说什么
I'm a giant with the flu. I don't know what to say.
请两周假
Take two weeks off!
找个地方 做你想做的事 好吗
Go somewhere, do what you need to do, okay?
但跟里格斯的比赛结束之后
But you have a tournament
第二天你还有一场锦标赛
the day after that match with Riggs...
不论胜败 你必须出场
...and, win or lose, you're gonna be there.
好的 谢谢
Okay, thank you.
你知道的 如果你输了
And just so you know, if you lose,
我永远不会原谅你
I will never forgive you.
天啊 赖瑞
Oh, Jesus, Larry.
事太多了 难怪我的身体快垮了
It's too much. No wonder my body's falling apart.
好吧 如果你需要
Okay, if there's somebody that you need...
我给那个谁打电话
...that you want me to call...
我可以帮你打
...I can call her.
不 我不想打给谁
No, there's nobody.
如果你误认为他傻
And if you mistake him for a fool,
到头来你会发现你才是真傻
you may end up looking like one yourself.
无论是穿着裙子 用雨伞打球
Whether he's wearing a dress, playing with an umbrella...
还是跟本赛季不可缺少的助手比赛
...or sporting this season's
助手是一群羊
must-have accessory, a flock of sheep...
鲍比还未尝败绩
...Bobby has not lost a match yet.
随着里格斯马戏团造访下一个城市
And as the Bobby Riggs circus moves on to the next town...
人们不禁在想
...people are beginning to wonder
他的对手在干什么
what has happened to the opposition.
她不能发声吗 她逃离了这个国家吗
Has she choked? Has she fled the country?
自从在森林山感染病毒退赛后
After withdrawing from Forest Hills with a virus, nobody...
没人见过比利·简·金的踪影
...has seen even the ghost of Billie Jean King.
嘿 你要去哪儿
Hey! Where are you going?
她要去哪儿
Where is she going?
我猜
My guess?
去休斯顿
Houston.
她知道什么时间
She does know what time this is...
是的 我告诉过你了
Yes, I told you.
她退出了吗
Has she pulled out?
她之前病了
She was ill.
对不起我来晚了 先生们
Sorry I'm late, gentlemen.
亲爱的 流感好了吗
Hey, honey, how's the flu?
-流感吗 -我听说你病了
- Flu? - I heard you were ill.
不 别相信报纸上的任何话 鲍比
No. Don't believe everything you read in the papers, Bobby.
但谢谢你的花 我把它们送给罗茜了
But thank you for the flowers. I gave 'em to Rosie.
我转手就给了垃圾桶
And I put 'em in the trash.
哦
Oh.
比利·简
Billie Jean.
杰克
Jack.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
杰克是我请来做ABC电视台评论员的
Jack's my choice of commentator for ABC.
杰克吗
Jack?
这可不行
Oh, that won't work.
比利·简 没人抱怨
Now, Billie Jean, no one's complaining
罗茜做实况直播
about Rosie doing the play-by-play.
罗茜不像某人 没有处心积虑地
Well, Rosie hasn't continually
想毁掉女子网球
tried to dismantle women's tennis.
你夸大我的影响了 比利·简
You overstate my influence, Billie Jean.
你投票反对我们加入美国草地网球协会 杰克
You blackballed us from the USLTA, Jack.
我们帮了你一个忙 那是个差劲的组织
We did you a favor. Lousy organization.
反正我选了杰克
Jack's my choice.
一定是个有力的评论员
Sure make for a punchy commentator.
我不比了
I won't play.
我为这场比赛花了七十五万美元
Look, I just spent $750,000 on this event.
你不能在比赛的前一天退出
You can't pull out the day before the match!
谁说的
Says who?
不如这样
Say...
我们能不能单独聊聊
...I wonder if we could...
单独聊聊 就我们俩
...have a word, just the two of us.
比利·简
Billie Jean...
我知道我们意见不合
...I know we've had our differences,
但那都已经过去了
but that's behind us.
现在是你和鲍比的事
This is between you and Bobby now.
鲍比吗
Bobby?
鲍比只是个小丑
Oh, Bobby's a clown.
整件事对他来说是一出表演 杰克
This whole thing's an act for him, Jack.
你也知道的
You know that.
有你在情况就不同了 来真的了
With you it's different. It's for real.
SSK字幕组
什么意思
What do you mean?
SSK字幕组
我觉得你不尊重女性
I don't think you respect women.
我婚姻幸福已经32年了
I've been happily married for 32 years.
我认为你喜欢女人待在厨房和卧室里
No, I think you like us in the kitchen and the bedroom.
我觉得你是个绅士 我是认真的
I think you are a gentleman, and I mean that.
谢谢 从你嘴里说出的赞扬
Thank you. I'll take my compliments
我照单全收
where I can from you.
但女人如果胆敢想得到更多
It's when we dare to want a little bit more.
哪怕从你那里得到一丁点
Just a little bit of what you've got.
你就忍受不了
That's what you can't stand.
真的吗
Oh. Really?
真的
Yeah.
现在居然要你向美国观众
And to have you telling the American public
解读每个发球怎么样
what to read into every serve?
解读每一分
Every point?
对不起 杰克
I'm sorry, Jack.
如果你做评论员 我不比了
If you're commentating, I'm not playing.
你那样做会让人们怎么看
How do you think that's gonna make
伟大的比利·简·金
the great Billie Jean King look?
居然因为不喜欢评论员
Backing out at the last minute
而在最后一刻选择退出
just because she didn't like the commentator?
我想会跟人们怎么看
I think it's pretty similar to how
伟大的杰克·克雷默非常相似
it'll make the great Jack Kramer look.
因为他没能参与
Shutting the whole thing down
比赛就被关停了
because he didn't get to participate.
不 不会这样的
No. That's not gonna happen.
你不会这么做
You're not gonna do this.
这对你来说意义重大 你和你的姐妹们
This means too much to you. You and your Sisterhood.
这么重要的事
You'd never throw it
你不会放弃的 你不会
over something like this. You won't.
记得上一次你觉得我吓唬你吗
Do you remember the last time you thought I was bluffing?
一美元
One dollar.
你知道一名好选手
You know the difference between
和一名伟大的选手之间的区别吗
a good player and a great?
伟大的选手从不意气用事
The great players never let emotion get in the way.
意气只会影响比赛
It messes with their game.
抱歉 鲍比
Sorry, Bobby.
赛前有什么想法吗 比利·简
Any last minute thoughts, Billie Jean?
你会赢下比赛吗
Are you going to win?
当然她会赢
Of course she's gonna win.
对阵鲍比·里格斯这个老家伙 当然赢
Against an old guy like Bobby Riggs, sure.
让她打罗茜沃尔或纳斯塔赛
Let her play Rosewall or Nastase.
男人打得更好 就这么简单
Men are better. End of story.
我不是说女人更好
I'm not saying women are better.
我从未说过
I've never said that.
我是说我们应该得到尊重
I'm saying we deserve some respect.
远比鲍比·里格斯或是你给我们的尊重要多
More than Bobby Riggs or you are giving us.
先生 你有女儿吗
Sir, do you have a daughter?
或是姐妹 你一定有妈妈吧
Or a sister? You sure as heck have a mother.
你爸爸好过你妈妈吗
Is your father better than your mother?
难道就因为他是男人吗 你持此想法吗
Just because he's a man? Do you believe that?
不
No.
但你就是这么说的
But that's what you're saying...
无论你是不是那样想
whether you think you are or not.
如果我打败鲍比·里格斯 你能不这样说了吗
If I beat Bobby Riggs, will you stop saying it?
好
Okay.
先生 我会让你兑现的
Sir, I'm gonna hold you to that.
如果我再看到你 我会让你兑现的
If I see you, I'm gonna hold you to that.
谢谢 今天到此为止
Thank you. That's it for today.
我们比赛见
We'll see you at the match.
我们启动这场秀吧
Let's get this show on the road.
给你 鲍比
Here you go, Bobby.
-爸爸 -嗯
- Dad? - Yeah?
我打算在这儿看比赛
I'm just gonna watch it here.
什么意思 重要时刻要到了 就是今天
What do you mean? This is it. This is the day.
抱歉 我
I'm sorry. I'm...
我不去了
...I'm not coming.
你不会觉得我要输吧 儿子
You don't think I'm gonna lose, do you, kiddo?
不是
No.
你会打得很好 你不需要我
You'll do great. You don't need me.
祝你好运 爸爸
Good luck, Dad.
这条是图森的詹妮弗发来的
This one's from Jennifer in Tucson.
“祝你好运 比利·简 我们都支持你”
"Good luck, Billie Jean, we're all rooting for you."
这条是纽约的安妮发来的
This one's from Annie from New York.
“加油 比利 我们知道你会赢”
"Go, Billie, we know you're gonna win."
你变瘦了 我必须再改改
You've lost weight. I have to take this in.
-没时间了 -有时间
- We don't have time. - We have time.
你觉得怎么样 亲爱的
How you feeling, honey?
你需要什么吗 水
Do you need anything? Water?
不需要 谢谢
No, I'm good, thank you.
离比赛开始还有二十分钟
Twenty minutes to game time.
罗茜·卡萨尔斯 请你到演播室
Rosie Casals, they need you in the studio.
你赢定了
You're gonna kill him.
伙计们一会儿见
I'll see you guys in a bit.
演播好运
Good luck out there.
我必须问清楚 你真的打算
Now, I have to ask, do you really intend to
强穿蓝色小山羊皮鞋
inflict blue suede shoes...
出现在九千万观众面前吗
...on ninety million members of the viewing public?
多少人 上帝啊 比利·简
How many? Oh, my God. Billie Jean!
猫王能穿
If they're good enough for Elvis,
我也能穿
they're good enough for me.
好吧 什么地方不对劲
Well, something's off.
-我觉得是鞋 -不是鞋
- And I think it's the shoes. - It's not the shoes!
发型吗
Your hair?
妈妈 爸爸 这是玛丽莲
Mom, Dad, this is Marilyn.
我的发型师
My hairdresser.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
我知道一个重要的道理
Well, if there's one thing I know, it's...
千万别打扰一个女人和她的发型师
...never get between a woman and her hairdresser.
真幽默 确实是
Very funny. Yes indeed.
走吧 我们去找座位
Come on. Let's find our seats.
我带你们过去
Here. I'll take you up there.
好运
Good luck.
谢谢
Thank you.
让他们好瞧
Yeah, give 'em heck.
比利·简 我会回来带你上场
Billie Jean, I'll be back to take you to the court.
好的
All right.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
你的发型师 哈
Your hairdresser, huh?
我还能怎么说
What was I supposed to say?
你是对的
No, you're right.
我就是来做发型的
That's why I'm here.
来吧
Come on.
就是这样 看起来好极了
Yeah, just like that. That looks great.
拉上拉链 厉害了
Yep, zip her up. Oh, boy!
要让“糖爸爸”商标面对摄像机
We need the "Sugar Daddy" Facing camera.
-嗯 -必须能看到
- Mmm-hmm. - We got to see that.
我得握住棍吗
Do you want me to hold it from the stick?
-呃 -我要这样握吗
- Uh... - Am I gonna hold it that way?
看起来不错
That looks great.
我们还得为比赛做准备
We're trying to prepare for the match.
那样摄像机能照清楚
So the camera can see it.
高高举着 漂亮
Yeah, up high. Beautiful.
我会举得又高又漂亮
I'll get it up nice and high.
-好了 谢谢 -比赛加油
- We got it. Thank you. - Have a great match.
谢谢 谢谢 女士们 场上见
Thank you. Thank you, ladies. See you out there.
场上见 干得不错
See you out there. Good work.
为了男人而战 鲍比
Do it for the men, Bobby.
觉得还好吗
Wow. You good?
是的 准备好上战场了
Yeah! I'm ready for battle.
预备 霍华德 直播倒数 五
Stand by, Howard. We are live in five...
四 三
...four... three...
接下来播出的是
The following is an exclusive presentation
ABC体育台独家呈现
of ABC Sports.
在德克萨斯休斯顿阿斯托洛球场举行的
Live from the Astrodome in Houston, Texas...
网球
性别之战
网球性别之战
...the Tennis Battle of the Sexes,
比利·简·金对阵鲍比·里格斯
Billie Jean King vs. Bobby Riggs.
比利简金
VS
鲍比里格斯
多么难得一见的场面
What a scene it is!
休斯顿阿斯托洛球场
The Houston Astrodome...
迄今为止已经举办过世界上
...where up till now they've played
除网球之外的各类体育赛事
almost every sport in the world except tennis.
在赛事全景直播中
But in this panoramic scene, a happening.
有大牌乐队
With the big band here,
有舞动的拉拉队和其他各种精彩
with dancing cheerleaders, and all of the rest.
令人难以置信的是
It's hard to believe, but probably
约有超过三万人涌入体育场
more than 30,000 people are in this arena...
打破了世界上有史以来的
...for an all-time-record tennis audience
网球观赛人数记录
anywhere in the world.
我是一头男性沙文主义猪
数到五放大
And zoom in on five.
那是个神父吗
Is that a priest?
是的 如果鲍比赢了 她会改随夫姓
Yeah. If Bobby wins, she takes the groom's surname.
但如果比利·简赢了 丈夫随她的姓
But if Billie Jean wins, the groom takes her name.
还能反转 有意思
Little flip-flop. Oh, boy.
比利·简在哪儿
Where's Billie Jean?
有人能
Can somebody...
谁知道她在哪儿
Does anybody know where she is?
什么意思 你跟丢了
What do you mean, you lost her?
她在修头发 马上就出来
She's getting a trim. She'll be right out.
是的 理发
Yeah, like a haircut.
我想你了
I missed you.
我知道
I know.
离比赛还有十分钟
Uh, ten minutes to game time!
留下来看比赛吗
Stay for the match?
-你确定吗 -是的
- Are you sure? - Yes.
求你
Please.
您能相信吗
There was, would you believe, a problem
我们一个播音员出状况了
about one of our announcers to be:
杰克·克雷默 知名的网球运动推进者
Jack Kramer. The famed tennis promoter.
知名的网球名宿
The famed tennis player of the past.
我们想要杰克·克雷默来 我们尊敬他
We wanted Jack Kramer. We respected him.
他本应该来直播的
He would have been on our telecast.
播放杰克·克雷默片段
Roll the Jack Kramer clip.
比利·简会爱死这个的
Billie Jean's gonna love this!
我想要声明一点
I want to make one thing clear.
我意识到我可能是个问题
When I realized that I was perhaps a problem...
如果她输给鲍比·里格斯
...I thought maybe Billie Jean
我觉得比利·简可能会
would want to use me as an excuse...
拿我当借口
...if she lost against Bobby Riggs.
ABC要作证
To ABC's credit...
他们说了 “你来吧 杰克”
...they said, "You call the shots, Jack,
“我们会站在你这边”
"We'll go along with you."
但是我自愿退出
But I'm withdrawing voluntarily...
而且我祝愿
...and I'm wishing
我的伙伴 鲍比·里格斯百分百好运
a hundred percent good luck to my pal, Bobby Riggs.
好的杰克 你知道我们有多尊重您
Okay, Jack, you know how much we respect you.
他们已经在等候区做好准备了
They are ready for you in the holding area.
我带你过去
I'll walk you down there.
我想自己去
I think I'm gonna go on my own.
-行吗 -好啊
- Okay? - Yeah.
运动包在房间里
The package is in the room.
比利 比利·简
Billie! Billie Jean!
这是为你准备的
This is for you.
好
All right.
先生们 走吧
Gentlemen, let's go.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
性别之战即将开始
the Battle of the Sexes is about to begin.
选手是六次温网冠军
Introducing six-time Wimbledon champion...
四次获得全美女子冠军
...four-time women's champion of the United States...
获得女子网球大满贯的
...winner of the Grand Slam of women's tennis...
比利·简·金
Billie Jean King!
比利·简·金有压倒性的
There is an overwhelming sentiment
人气
for Billie Jean King.
真是个非常迷人的年轻女士
Very attractive young lady...
而且有时候你会觉得
...and sometimes you get the feeling
她的头发从来没长过
that if she ever let her hair grow...
也从未摘下她的眼镜
...and took her glasses off,
好像和人在竞争好莱坞试镜
you'd have somebody vying for a Hollywood screen test.
-噢 鲍比·里格斯入场了 -啊
- Oh! Here comes Bobby Riggs. - Ah.
现在画面中就是他
You see him now in the picture.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
让我们欢迎大满贯冠军
please welcome Grand Slam champion...
网球名人堂的 鲍比·里格斯
...and Tennis Hall of Famer, Bobby Riggs!
一场大家期待已久的比赛
A long-awaited match,
鲍比·里格斯一直在
hustled and promoted...
为这场比赛不竭余力地造势
...ceaselessly and shrewdly by Bobby Riggs.
这就是鲍比
There's Bobby.
看这大阵仗 狂欢声还有喧闹声
The big act, the big bluster, the big noise.
现在他要和比利·简·金
Now he's got steeper competition
来一场惊险的比赛
with Billie Jean King.
真是疯了
This thing is nuts.
好了 镜头切回来 这是我们今晚的
All right, we're back on camera and this is our...
女网球专家 认出她了吗
...female expert tonight. Recognize her?
小罗茜·卡萨尔斯
Little Rosie Casals.
你说比利·简会在三盘内赢是吗
Now, you say Billie Jean will win in three sets?
是的 我确实这么想
Yes, I definitely think so.
我觉得她是个更好的网球选手
I think she's a better tennis player...
而且我认为考特和里格斯的比赛
...and I think what happened with the Court and Riggs match
今晚不会重演
will not happen tonight.
比利·简会打败他 绝对的
Billie Jean will beat him, definitely.
我给比利·简带了这个
Well, I got this beautiful lollipop
漂亮的棒棒糖
for Billie Jean.
我猜她会对我的高球上瘾的
I figure she's gonna be a sucker for my lob.
实际上 我也给你带了点儿东西 鲍比
I got something for you too, Bobby, actually.
这是给男权主义的终极礼物
It's the ultimate gift for a male chauvinist.
呃
Ugh...
给你
There you go.
噢 好吧 好吧
Oh, that's okay, that's okay.
比赛前还有什么话要说吗 鲍比
Any last words before the match, Bobby?
好 这场比赛是为了全世界所有
Well, this match is for all the guys
和我有同样感受的男人
around the world that feel as I do...
男人是王者 男人是至高无上的
...that the male is king, the male is supreme.
比利·简呢
Billie Jean?
不用废话了 开始吧
I'm done talking. Let's play.
噢
Oh!
Ooh!
他们开始比赛了
They have started the match.
比利·简发球
Service, Billie Jean.
零比十五
Love-15.
鲍比
Bobby.
-指望你挣大钱呢 -就这样
- Make us some money. - That a boy.
当然 这场比赛
This match, of course,
会在全世界通过卫星播放
is going by satellite all around the world.
十五平
15-all.
你会听到人群一整晚
And you'll hear the crowd responding all night
为了比利·简赢得的每一分欢呼
to every point won by Billie Jean.
好样的姑娘
Attagirl.
鲍比已经进入状态了
Bobby's already starting.
在比利赢后喊了一句“好样的姑娘”
Shouted "Attagirl" Right after Billie hit the winner.
当他要输的时候
When he starts losing,
我认为他不会说“好样的姑娘”
I don't think he's gonna say "Attagirl".
他很自信
He's confident.
不是所有人都是为比利·简来的
Not everybody is for Billie Jean.
有些是为了
Some are for
这个自称的男性沙文主义者而来
the self-proclaimed male chauvinist.
如果他输掉这场比赛 他就不得不输掉了男权
What he has to lose if he loses this match!
他就会回家
He'll have to go back
煮饭 做家务
to cooking and doing the housework.
比利·简·金赢下一局
Game, Billie Jean King,
观众们很开心
and the crowd loves it.
他们准备交换场地了
They're getting ready to exchange courts.
比利·简一比零领先
Billie Jean leads one game to love.
鲍比 你得脱掉那件该死的夹克
Bobby, you got to take that damn jacket off.
他们给了我两万呢 我得穿着
They gave me twenty G's. I got to keep it on.
我不管 你得脱下来
I don't care, you've got to take it off.
鲍比·里格斯一记好球
Nicely placed by Bobby Riggs.
我觉得她现在打得太保守了
I think she's too tentative at the moment.
那确实是问题
That's really the problem.
她的总体战略是什么呢
What is her overall strategy?
你和她非常熟
You're so close to her.
呃 从心理上来说
Well, psychologically
她更像是个压力型的选手
she's a better pressure player.
比利·简本质上是另一个鲍比·里格斯
Billie Jean's basically like another Bobby Riggs.
她很有计谋
She's a hustler.
她能抗住那种压力
She can take that type of pressure
并将同样的压力还给他
and give the same stuff back to him.
还是不压里格斯吗
Still no Riggs.
是
Right.
现在四十比十五
We're at 40-15.
很高兴看着那个老男人为了球来回跑
Fun to see the old man run for that one.
如果比利·简能一直让鲍比跑动
If Billie Jean can keep Bobby running,
我觉得他就会筋疲力尽
I think she could wear him down.
所以 鲍比·里格斯终于脱下了夹克
Hence, the jacket begins to be taken off by Bobby Riggs...
也许这个自大狂有些疲倦了
...and maybe the braggadocio a little bit reduced.
事实上里格斯
A concession to the fact that Riggs...
或许知道他要陷入品牌纷争了
...perhaps knows he's running into firm competition.
我们看到他吃了
I think he's gonna start taking
一些维生素
some of the vitamin pills.
他开始需要那些了
He's gonna start needing them.
鲍比的局点
Game point for Bobby.
罗茜 她看起来有些紧张
Rosie, she looks tense to me.
她有些紧张 毋庸置疑
She is tense. No doubt about that.
这是场非常重要的比赛
This is a very important match.
鲍比·里格斯突出重围
And Bobby Riggs breaks through.
第一个可能出现的转折点在
The first perhaps turning point in...
这场比赛的第一盘
...the first set of this match.
鲍比·里格斯领先比利·简·金
Bobby Riggs leading Billie Jean King.
他承受着压力
He had the pressure on him.
他的反应很棒
He responded very well.
但是比利·简那记球
And Billie Jean did not respond well
反应不是很好 鲍比·里格发球占先
on that shot. Advantage to Bobby Riggs.
好样的小伙子
Attaboy.
鲍比这记球真是太妙了
Marvelous shot by Bobby...
还有比利·简一记漂亮的挥拍
...and a great quick swing by Billie Jean.
金
里
格斯
比利的接招很棒 她做到了之前那样
Billie answering great. She did what she had to do...
而且她用自己的方式做到了 基恩
...and she did it her way, Gene.
鲍比·里格斯好球
And a great shot by Bobby Riggs.
妇女解放者不需要挑高球
结束了
There it is.
比利·简·金拿下第一盘
And the first set goes to Billie Jean King.
里
格斯
金
盘点
Point and set.
在这竞技场中的女人们都起立了
The women in this arena are standing
为比利·简·金加油
and cheering for Billie Jean King.
鲍比看起来不是很开心
Bobby doesn't look very happy.
他走路的时候有点儿低着头
He's sort of walking with his head down.
他在他的教练那里
I think he's gonna get a little strategy
得到了一些战略指导
from his coach over there.
他们有四分钟时间休息 霍华德
They have a four-minute break, Howard.
我猜我们都期待
I suppose we all expected to have
比赛中能有很多幽默元素
some high humor involved in it.
但是 好像这场比赛变成了一件
Instead, it seems to have become
非常 非常严肃的事 因为
a very, very serious thing, because...
鲍比·里格斯已经失去笑意了
...the comedy has gone out of Bobby Riggs.
第二盘第二局开始了
The second game of the second set has just begun...
鲍比·里格斯正在发球
...Bobby Riggs serving,
突破了比利·简·金的防守
having broken through Billie Jean King...
一比零 鲍比·里格斯落后
...one game to none in favor of Bobby Riggs.
比利·简正在寻找机会反击
And Billie Jean is seeking to strike back.
比利·简用高球扣击
Billie Jean is killing him
我就这么说吧 她在折磨他
with that overhand smash, I'll tell you that.
鲍比突然变成了处于劣势的一方 霍华德
Bobby suddenly has become an underdog, Howard.
是的 一些人在为他加油
Yes, some of them are cheering for him.
漂亮
Beautiful.
比利·简·金
Billie Jean King...
金
里
格斯
六比三 赢下了第二盘
...has won the second set, six games to three.
她领先两盘 二比零
She leads two sets to love...
目前为止 对于女士们来说 这真是个非常棒的夜晚
...and it's so far a very great night for the ladies.
鲍比·里格斯在为了他的网球生涯战斗
Bobby Riggs is fighting for his tennis life.
她现在充满自信
She's filled with confidence now.
好球
Great shot!
Marvelous shot!
四比二 鲍比落后
Bobby trails four games to two.
毫无疑问 比利·简
No question about it, Billie Jean has been
在比赛中成为了进攻方
the aggressor in this match.
他的手好像
I think we're having
出了点儿问题
a little problem with his hand.
他一直在拉扯他的手指
He keeps pulling on his fingers,
那意味着他的手抽筋了
and to me that says he's getting a cramp.
医生在查看他的
He's having the hand
手和手臂
and the arm looked at.
是受伤了吗
Is this an injury then?
是的
This is an injury.
因伤推迟五分钟
Five minutes delay for an injury.
我就知道会这样 我知道
I knew it would come to this. I knew...
鲍比会因为某些事下场
...Bobby would have to come down to something.
比如伤病
Like injuries.
关于鲍比·里格斯 我就这么说吧 罗茜
Let me say this about Bobby Riggs, Rosie.
今晚你们在言语上一直不放过他
You've gotten in all your licks tonight
这也没有什么
at the guy, and that's fine.
毕竟他也说了些男性沙文主义的话
And he made a lot of noise about male chauvinism and...
比如说 女人属于厨房
...the women belonged in the kitchen,
还有其他的
and all the rest.
但是他55岁了 他就是那样的人
But he is 55, and he's some kind of guy.
我同意 但是我并不认为
I agree. But I don't think
他属于球场
he belongs on the court...
同比利·简的才华相对比的话
...with somebody of Billie Jean's caliber.
好吧 现在
Well, the way it's proving
事实证明
out at the moment...
你是对的
...turns out that you are right,
如果比赛就这么结束的话
if it ends this way.
好的 鲍比准备好发球了 努力在第三盘追上
Okay, Bobby's ready to serve, trailing in the third set.
加油 鲍比 你之前说什么来着
Here we go, Bobby, what do you say?
干得好
Attaboy!
十五比零
15-love.
一个粉丝在大喊 “加油 鲍比宝贝”
One of the fans yelling, "Come on, Bobby baby!"
鲍比赢了一分
Bobby wins that point...
就在他开始努力突破比利·简的时候
...as he starts his fight to break through Billie Jean.
鲍比·里格斯反击成功
Bobby Riggs fights back and breaks through!
不管之前他的手抽筋了
Whether he had the hand cramp
还是没有
earlier or not...
他明显试图去
...what he obviously was trying to do
打破比利·简的良好势头
was break up Billie Jean's brilliant momentum.
嗯 好球
Mmm-hmm. Great shot.
听听观众们的声音
Listen to that crowd!
在为里格斯欢呼
Now cheering for Riggs.
对一个老男人来说还不坏
Not bad for an old man.
鲍比还有机会 罗茜
Bobby still has the break, Rosie.
比利·简赢得绝佳的一分
Marvelous point won by Billie Jean!
我说过 她很难对付的
I'll tell you, she's tough.
她正走回原位 她走路的时候
Walking back, she's walking
更像个男人
more like a male than a female.
-失误 -失误
- Out. - Out.
双发失误
Double fault.
你看到的
You're looking
是一个明显疲倦了的鲍比·里格斯
at an apparently tired Bobby Riggs.
看吧 比利·简·金
Look at how Billie Jean King
让他在场上不断奔跑着
has been running him over the court.
那就是她的核心战术
And that's been her principal tactic,
让他筋疲力尽
to wear him down.
棒
Yes!
-漂亮 -好球
- Beautiful! - Great shot.
哇
And, wham,
那真是我们看过的网球里
that's the kind of tennis we've had...
好极了 宝贝
Right on, baby!
她放弃了这球
She puts it away.
看啊
Look at that!
绝妙的移动
A brilliant move!
令人赞叹一球
Amazing shot.
她到了赛点
And she is at match point.
赛点
我真地希望杰克·克莱默在观看这场比赛
I really hope Jack Kramer is watching this
并且拿点儿什么硬家伙打自己的头
and will cement something in his head...
那个女人不是开玩笑
...that women are not some kind of joke.
鲍比·里格斯 为了他所有吹的牛皮战斗
Bobby Riggs... fights for his whole hustle.
支持比利 简  竞选总统
我低估了你
I underestimated you.
这场比赛成为了一个轰动的事件
It's the game that's become a cause celebre.
女性平等  权利平等
Equality for women. Equal rights.
比利·简为了美国网球公开赛的女性
It was Billie Jean who fought for equal pay for women...
同薪同酬而斗争 她做到了
...in the U.S. Open tennis tournament and got it.
比利·简·金自己一个人打完了比赛
Billie Jean King played her own game,
一个人休息 不交流
resting up, being non-communicative...
但是她的精神
...but preparing herself mentally
情感和生理上
and emotionally and physically...
都为这场和鲍比·里格斯的精彩对决做好了准备
...for a stunning performance against Bobby Riggs.
弗兰克·吉福德现在想和你做个直播 来吧
Frank Gifford wants you live right now. Come on.
弗兰克·吉福德想要和你做一个
Frank Gifford wants to do a live interview
直播采访 他就在那里
with you. He's just over here.
等一下 一小下
Just in a minute. In a minute.
超级明星夫人
Madame Superstar!
-恭喜您 -噢
- Congratulations. - Aww.
我们走吧
Now, come on.
舞会没了你没法开始
The dancing can't start without you.
我还没准备好
I'm not sure I'm ready for all this.
我觉得你比自己想的准备得更好
I think you may be more ready than you know.
时代变了
Times change.
你应该知道 是你改变了他们
You should know. You just changed them.
有一天
Someday...
想成为谁 想爱谁
...we will be free to be who we are...
会成为我们的自由
...and love who we love.
但是现在
But now...
该参加庆祝舞会了
...time to join the dance.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
比利·简·金
Billie Jean King!